[Music]
Hey, hey, hey.
Heat.
[Music]
Hello, good evening, good day everybody
and welcome to the latest episode of Ask
Abijit. This is episode 292 and we are
going to discuss geopolitics today. It's
going to be entirely based on super chat
and live chat. So let us see who all we
have on the live stream with us this
fine day. I can see
Makin, Vladimir Putin, Deepipika, Vish
Pala, Aayush Yadav, Kuml, Geopolitical
the way from Indor, Suas, Reddi, uh,
Deepipika, Somi, Jane, Anahita, Kennel,
Aayush Singh, Bruce Wayne, Random Skull,
Anime is enjoying my book series. Well,
thank you so much. I'm glad you're
enjoying it. More people should enjoy
it. Uh Vinach Rajat Duhan Vikash PJ Chat
DSP That Relationship Guy Harm Itachi
Space I Painter Om Beered Hello uh
Freedom from Outcome from Toronto
Ultimate Power Vish Pala once again J
Akash B Akash BA uh Tushar Kalborgi The
Knowledge Priest Chhat DSP Sergeant
Skylan Dave Duv Durya Mystic SK K AK J
Digshit Abidai Singh Mav Mav Chin Pratam
Sharma Aus in439 from Agra Namaste sir
Pratam Sharma soldier boy animals from
laugh animals for laugh from Mumbai
Akash ba ashwani may Ujiha YT IP_1s
Nikesh dahal pranam panam wladimir Putin
well hello tanesh pandit naray hijukesh
uttar Jagdish Mali Tushar Kalborgi
Itachi Space HB um Adita Singh Takur
Shama Prasad Kuml aky
uh Shrih Harsh Shrih Harsh Moil
satellite Vikas PJ once again Miss Tupi
Namaste Shrih once again Bal Bal key
today good evening PD dark night says
good morning well good morning to you
Junadas good evening from Assam well
good to have Junadas Rush Rash God
Anurag Gore Sneha Kishor Mulch Chandani
Hello uh Jascaran Singh Ajay Kumar Akula
Bi Musarat Ashtavakra
and everyone else all right okay enough
of uh greeting everyone I welcome you
all to the live li live stream and let's
take some questions do we have any
interesting questions okay let's see
let's go with Mlevin do you think the
tariff regime change situation in our
around our neighborhood would be
different if Prime Minister Modi had
full majority. No, it would not matter.
Um
the tariffs is something that's being
applied globally by Trump, right? And
the regime changes will happen even more
vigorously
would have happened even more vigorously
if Mr. Prime Minister Modi had full
majority. Uh anyway, uh it doesn't
really matter whether Prime Minister
Modi is full majority or not. The US is
going to do what it will do. So it would
not have made any significant difference
right okayash Sharma says so my tweet on
Aratai Zoho's logo looks like a
Microsoft ripoff even the colors had
prime minister used coup it would have
survived well okay I'm not going to
comment on Zoho's logo and all that I'm
not sure I'm not I can't recall what it
looks like uh look it's it's natural for
anyone to be kind of uh if it's if it's
the case It's natural for anyone to be
inspired knowingly or unknowingly by the
most successful companies in the world.
So I see nothing wrong with that. In
case that is that is indeed true that's
okay. And if prime minister had used
coup it would have survived possibly.
Possibly. But the problem also is that
coup wasn't a good user experience. I
had a coup account. I tried using it. It
was painful to use coup. It was painful.
It was not a good user experience. This
is one thing that Indians need to learn.
If you create something, it has to be
world class. Then don't blame Indians.
If Indians stop adopting it, if your
product isn't good, your products that
you make have to be world class. Coup
was a terrible user experience. Compared
to Twitter, it was it was it was painful
to use. So yeah if I would say that you
know coup would have survived if they
had given a better user experience if
they had made made the app more user
friendly we cannot expect Indians to
adopt substandard products when they
already used to American uh products
that are the you know the best that have
the best standards in the world. So if
India wants to compete it has to compete
at global standards and not push
substandard stuff for Indians. Indians
won't adopt that. So that's something
that Indian uh developers need to need
to be cognizant of. They need to realize
this.
Adi Aayou says why do you always refrain
to talk about nose? What is nose? What's
a nose? I'm sorry. What is that
nose? I don't discuss noses here. I
either discuss science, geopolitics or
history. So I'm not sure what you're
saying, sir. If you want to say
something, say it clearly. Otherwise
well what
a Rahul says love all right thank you so
much a Rahul G thank you so much I
really appreciate that thank you so much
thank you so much
a Rahul says I I feel we are very far
from reaching the 2047 goal there are no
competent leaders in India no one to the
level that is required and the system is
designed to make the country fail it is
so sad it is true we face immense
problems that are internal problems more
than the external problems the United
States now deciding to contain India
more than the problem of Pakistan which
is a permanent perennial terror threat
the problem of China which which doesn't
want India to rise to grow and whatever
other problems we face more than that
the bigger problems are the problems
within the structural problems India's
system is designed to make India fail
India's entire system is designed to
ensure that India doesn't rise India
doesn't rise to its fullest potential
not even half the potential India should
stay mediocre. India should remain at 10
15% of its potential. That is what the
system is designed. It's designed in
that way and all the internal problems
that we have. All the artificial
divisions that have been created in the
country, Indians keep fighting each
other all the time. Indians the
education system has endowed Indians
with this these set of characteristics
and qualities. Indians have this urge to
keep arguing with each other. They feel
that arguing and raising your voice in
argument makes you look very
intelligent. No, success makes you int
look intelligent. Not your verbal
victories and arguments. No one cares
about that. But Indians have been made
to believe that all these fake victories
are real victories. I defeated him in a
verbal argument. Yeah. Good job, sir.
Good job. Who cares? Yeah. So, there are
all these problems and there are no
there are very few there are very few
competent leaders in India.
I wouldn't say there are none at all.
There are extremely few competent
leaders in India. Um we would certainly
require far better leaders than what we
have right now. Um Prime Minister Modi,
I would say that we are very lucky that
we have him who is currently leading the
country. I hope that he'll well he leads
for as long as as possible but we need
to have better leaders coming up in the
pipeline. I can see a few, but it would
be great if every state could throw up
four, five top class leaders, but that's
not happening because the system is
designed to
to seek and destroy talent and push
forth mediocrity. So yes, we have all
these issues and yet we have to find a
way to to win somehow. So it's sad. I
know it's sad, but but there's no point
us sitting and crying because it's sad.
We have to find solutions. We have to
find solutions. We have to find a way to
succeed despite all the odds.
ICMBB says, "How could Ladak have been
proactively dealt with?" Nothing. What
is being done is right. See, Ladak has a
population of 300,000, 200,000. I don't
know what the population is. It's less
than a million. Yeah, it's a big
territory. It's a very sensitive place,
strategically very sensitive. It's on
the border between India and Chinese
occupied Tibet. China has already taken
a couple of bites out of Liddak, right?
As we know oxai chain is Ladak but China
has China currently occupies it because
of the generosity and magnanimity of
Shinu and so many other issues
and now we have aspiring Zalinskis who
are trying to create more trouble in
Ladak. So Ladak used to be part of Jammu
and Kashmir. It was completely
suppressed by the governments that would
that would sit in the Kashmir valley in
shrineagar
right and Ladak was essentially a
hostage of of the valley. Now in 2019
the government of India they decided to
transform Ladak into a separate union
territory and the people of Ladak are
happy. I am not inventing these stories.
I have been to Ladak multiple times.
Okay. It's one of my most favorite parts
of India. I have been to Ladak multiple
times. I've spoken to people there. I've
spent significant time in Ladak. I know
that people are really happy with the
changes that has happened. But now this
Wangchuk fellow
h a foreign agent, aspiring Zalinski,
he wants to create trouble over here,
right? He's saying we need statehood. A
statehood. You want statehood with
300,000 people. Yeah. What next? Dharavi
should be a state. Dharavi has a
population of more than a million. Make
Dhavi a state now. Yeah. Everybody will
now decide that we should we should have
a stateood. Who the hell is he to claim
that to to decide that Ladak needs
statethood? And by making Ladak a state,
you will have then and he wants the
sixth schedule in Ladak, which means
that no matter even if you want to
construct a new road, a new new arterial
highway, um a bridge, whatever, we will
need to then the government will then
need to take permission from people like
him, right?
And there are lots of these influencers
these Dhuvarati kind of people who are
supporting this Wangchuk fellow right
now. Uh so what has been done has been I
mean the only more proactive thing I can
think of is that Wangchuk should have
been thrown into prison like a year ago
when he started all this nonsense.
Whatever I think what has been done is
is correct and India needs to be very
careful about these foreign agents.
There are plenty there are plenty of
aspiring Zelinskis in this country and
we need to deal with these people
effectively.
Uchiasa says why doesn't the US have
military bases in Thailand, Laos,
Cambodia given the fact that they are
significantly very less on hard power
score. Um see you don't the US decides
where to have military bases depending
on what they want to achieve not on not
the basis of hard power score. If they
have bases in let's say Japan and South
Korea it is to deny something to China.
It is to encircle China. If they have
Taiwan as a unsinkable aircraft carrier,
it is to once again contain China. It's
to create these island chains
that hem in the Chinese navy.
When it comes to Thailand, there's no
point strategically to have military
bases there. I mean, whatever they want
to achieve is already achieved. They
don't need more military bases beyond
what they have in South Korea, Japan,
and um Taiwan. Taiwan is different a
different different case but similar
case once again so it doesn't make sense
from a geopolitical perspective from a
strategic perspective to put extra
military bases there military bases cost
a lot of money I I know the US has a
tremendous amount of money but even then
money is valuable you just don't go go
around throwing it around so when it
comes to different nations you have
different approaches towards these
nations even if there are your vasals
it's not necessary that you have to put
military bases in every vasal's
territory right
That's how it goes.
Okay. ADB says, "I got to know about BB
Lal and his work only because of you."
Oh, wow. Okay. I'm glad. I'm glad. And I
bought one of the books of his that you
recommended. I like your point of
digging deep in verification of sources.
Learned a lot. Learned a lot. Learned a
lot. Sincere gratitude and thank you.
Well, I'm I'm so glad that you did go
into the the work of Dr. BB Lal.
Fantastic books. As you will know,
you've bought bought one of his books.
Fantastic. I agree that you need to dig
deep. You need to verify sources for
yourself. Don't just depend on people's
opinions. No matter how much you like
those people, right? Do your own due
diligence. Do your own research. That's
how you grow as a person. That's how you
learn as a person. So, I'm so glad that
you've done that you are doing this and
you are very welcome, sir. Thank you so
much.
Sergeant Skylin says, "Cavari 2.0 by God
with single crystal blade. My thoughts
will it match GE414 engines? I think
it's fantastic. Absolutely fantastic.
So, uh this is first of all understand
this is not the final product. This is a
work in progress. This is a work in
progress. The Godidge uh engine is
something that they are in the process
of developing. Whatever they have
achieved thus far is what they have
displayed in whatever place they
displayed it. So, it's a it's a
derivative of the cavary engine. That's
what one hears. It is being taken
forward by Godidge. Single crystal
blades. Fantastic. Uh will it match the
GE414 engines? I think eventually it
will even surpass the GE414 engines. But
we have to give it some time. We have to
give it 5 10 years I suppose. Um what's
the what's the current output of this
engine in terms ter terms of kilontons
of force? I'm not really sure. Let's
shall we check it out? Let's let's uh
check it out together. Uh cavary
derivative Godidge right. Godidge
Godridge cavary derivative
engine what's the deal with this
so um Godidge cavary derivative engine
D1 is a dry dry it's a dry it doesn't
have u you know okay it's a dry engine
it doesn't have after burners okay turbo
jet engine recently entered seated
production with good aerospace
delivering the first unit in 2025 the
GTRE it's going to be lighter and more
fuel efficient than the engines with
after burners. Okay, it's going to be
it's intended for unmanned UCAVs,
unmanned combat aerial vehicles, other
endurance based platforms such as the
Gatak and Okay, so this is a this is
good progress. So, it's going to be used
for uh UCAVs and u the stealth UCAVs
such as Gatak. Okay, so this is simply
one step in the way forward. Um what's
the what's the output? What's the
output? 48 kon newtons. Some video says
48 kontons. Uh what does this say? What
does the Wikipedia article say? After
burning blah blah blah. Okay, this is
the cavi the original one. Okay, fine.
Uh the goodidge delivers caviar
derivative D1 big win. What are the
specs? Show us the specs.
Okay, I don't need your history. I need
the specs.
150 blah blah etc. Okay. So, caviar
derivative is 46 to 52 konton. All
right. When you have it with after
burner, it's going to have 90 kon. I
think that's the one that you need for
fighter fighter jets. So, it's under
development with Safh. Okay. So, it's
it's a it's a encouraging step forward
by Godidge. I think they should not stop
the development. Even if GTR is working
with Safh to devel to to develop the
afterburner version, what God should do
is first of all serialize the
production. ensure that each engine that
is delivered is high quality and then
take this forward develop a version that
has after burner capabilities and so on.
So yeah um so it's a it's a work in
progress. It's not the final product by
any by any means.
Abhishek Singh says if India and
Pakistan engage in a full-scale conflict
in Kashmir is there a possibility of
this becoming Ukraine like situation?
What's the outcome for India? Well it
depends on several factors.
uh look in a conventional conflict
Pakistan is going to get squashed and it
can't become Ukraine unless we decide
that we want to we want a slow war
scenario which we don't from our
perspective the conflict should end in
48 to 72 hours less than a week's time
definitely right it should be a rapid
achievement of the objectives once a
conflict start you need starts you need
to have clear objectives of what is the
end state that you desire
And once you know what the end state is,
you need to achieve it as rapidly as
possible. So I don't think India will
want to engage in a slow war situation,
long war scenario.
So depending based on the current
capabilities of the two countries, it
should be very simple for India to to
end the conflict within like less than
less than a week for sure and achieve
whatever outcomes we want to achieve. Is
it P? Is it the destruction of something
or the other or whatever? Yeah. Uh the
next time there's a conflict, there has
to be a change of territory. Otherwise,
the Pakistanis will keep on crying that
we won, right? Uh
but in what scenarios can it become
Ukraine like situation? If the US
decides to send aid to Pakistan, in that
case Pakistan may end up being
reinforced constantly by the Americans
and in that case it can become a a
Ukraine like situation or if somebody
else for example China for whatever
reason if it decides that that Pakistan
needs to be reinforced. So if they keep
sending supplies, if the Pakistanis
after a week they they've run out of
arms, ammunition supplies, whatever, but
the Americans start sending supplies or
the Chinese send supplies or both do it
in that case it can turn out to be that
kind of a scenario which is not good for
India. Which is why we need to achieve
the objectives very rapidly. Don't wait
for someone to come to Pakistan's
rescue. If you if if the conflict lasts
more than a week, two weeks, then it
will it will give enough time for other
nations to potentially come to
Pakistan's rescue. Which is why we need
to be very clear as of right now before
any conflict starts that if a conflict
happens again whenever it does happen
what are the objectives that we need to
achieve as rapidly as possible
what what what constitutes victory
that's what we need to be very clear
about and of course then there is the
nuclear scenario the nuclear blackmail
scenario that also we have to uh factor
into our calculations obviously uh this
time when the operation Synindur
conflict happened clearly we called the
Pakistani nuclear bluff and uh they they
did not come anywhere close to
operationalizing their nuclear
blackmail. So I think the nuclear
factory is going to be something that
you know despite what whatever Pakistan
says that we are a nuclear power or
whatever I don't think they are that
stupid that they will try to use nuclear
weapons which will guarantee full
complete destruction of Pakistan.
So I think we can keep the nuclear
threat aside and we need to have a very
clear understanding of what constitutes
victory in the next conflict. And if we
have that clear understanding of what
constitutes victory, we need to achieve
that at in the shortest amount of time.
It has to be a blitzkrieg operation next
time.
Godliness says Trump never wears
anything except the US flag on his coat,
but for the first time he was wearing a
golden fighter jet b while wearing the
Pakistani leadership. Was this some
subtle message? Maybe the Americans have
decided they will supply more F-16s to
Pakistan. Is that a possibility?
Everything is a possibility. All
possibilities are on the table right
now. Uh the Pakistanis are essentially
signaling that they are selling their
country off piece by piece to the US. uh
the Pakistani general or what Munir the
Munir guy the the dictator of Pakistan
he went to Trump with a box full of
minerals right here's what here's a
sample of what you will uh acquire from
Pakistan that sort of thing so Pakistan
is very happy to sell off their
countries piece by piece and in return
for that I'm sure there's a deal there's
some kind of a deal that has been uh
reached between Trump and the Pakistanis
maybe there's going to be more jets for
Pakistan more F-16s or Who knows even
F-35s I'm not sure. Uh so it looks like
there is some some signaling that Trump
did by putting that that golden uh
fighter jet b on his lapel.
So maybe it's a subtle message. We'll
have to see. So I will not be surprised
if the US in the coming days or weeks
announces that they are selling I don't
know a certain number of fighter planes
to Pakistan brand new F-16s or maybe
some maybe F-35s. I'm not sure. I will
not be surprised if that happens in the
next few days or weeks.
Uh Teen Talks Dharma says, "Is the
Russian avanguard system as good as the
say breakthrough?" I'm not sure. I've
not looked into the specific
specifications. Uh let's do it if you
want. Right. Russian avanguard system.
Yeah. What's the deal? It's a hypersonic
glide missile vehicle HGV with the
travels at speeds exceeding mark 20
carrying a nuclear conventional payload
launched by an ICBM. It detaches from
the missile. It's it's a maneuvering MV
kind of thing, right? It's a glide
vehicle. Okay. It detach detaches from
the missile and glides through the
atmosphere performing sharp maneuvers to
evade missile defense systems. Russia
unveiled it in 2018. has been putting it
into service since late 2018 early 2019
carrying it on heavy ICBMs like the RS28
Sarmat. So it can travel at frightening
speeds mark 20 to mark 27 and it
performs evasive maneuvers at these
hypersonic speeds. These are essentially
re-entry speeds not hypersonics
um boost glide system and so on. It can
uh yeah and it will obviously carry uh
nuclear warheads.
So that's what it says. Now the Russians
will know better than us how good the
system is. If it's been deployed, it
means that it must be really good. I
expect so it looks like it's a very good
system from whatever we see. Prashant
says, "Is the UN less relevant? Will
these speeches by diplomats help?" The
UN, what's the relevance? What what does
it achieve in the world? It's a talk
shop. Once a year everyone gets together
at the UN and leaders from across the
world come and deliver a speech from
their podium. In some cases like when
Prime Minister Netanyahu delivered a
speech most of the people left the hall
because they didn't want to listen to
him. Right? But when that al-Qaeda
terrorist the Syrian leader the current
Syrian dictator when he delivered the
his speech everyone sat there and
listened to him. Well what sort of a
hypocrisy is this right? And then you
have the the what's his name? Sharif the
Sharif guy Pakistan he went and gave a
gave an address to the UNGA and then
there was back and forth between India
and Pakist what's the point of all this
I don't understand I don't know the
relevance of the UN what does it achieve
for the world does it actually achieve
peace has it been a able to broker some
kind of a peace deal in Ukraine has it
been able to broker some kind of peace
deal somewhere else maybe between Israel
and uh Iran has it been able to ensure
that there is peace in the in in West
Asia, it does nothing. It's got soldiers
stationed in various parts of Africa.
Okay, fantastic.
So, the UN is irrelevant actually. And I
have an episode of uh of geo strategy in
which I've spoken about the UN. What's
the relevance of the UN? No relevance.
So, these speeches by diplomats, they
what what what
what's the role? What what's the what's
the meaning? What's the importance of
these speeches by diplomats? It's
essentially messaging to the world what
our stand is at the at the UN General
Assembly because when someone speaks at
the UN General Assembly, typically
people listen. People are more uh prone
to listening to you if you speak over
there compared to somewhere else. So
essentially it's a place where you can
voice your opinions and tell the world
what your stand is. That's all.
AI productivity magnet says how and
where will this multipolar conflict and
which multipolar conflict which one is
there a conflict a multipolar conflict
going on right now
are you talking about the new cold war
that's going to go on for a long time as
long as I'm not sure what you're asking
sir which multipolar conflict right now
we have the Ukraine conflict that's
going on we also have a recently frozen
uh conflict between Israel and Iran that
kind of is uh frozen right now.
Excuse me. And what else do we have? We
don't have any other conflicts going on
right now. We have a cold warlike
situation like a cold war 2.0, but I'm
not sure if that's what you're talking
about. So, please be a little more
specific.
I cannot read your mind, sir. Okay. All
right. Uh Adi Au says, "How do you
retain so much knowledge? What's the
trick?"
I only retain the information about what
I find interesting. I read all kinds of
stuff. I forget most of it. I forget
most of it. I only retain
the knowledge what you what do you call
of whatever I find interesting. Those
connections that that automatically get
made in the mind uh that's what remains.
The rest of the stuff that I don't find
interesting I I forget it. So I may
forget I may not have any recollection
of what I read even even half an hour
after I read it if it's not interesting.
So it's so I give myself the permission
to forget and that's why I'm able to
retain whatever I find interesting and
that's I suppose is how I retain
whatever knowledge I do retain sir.
Uh swastik MKkesh says is independent
Balojasthan possible after um the fact
that the US Pakistan relations have
currently improved and the US is arming
Pakistan. There's no question of
independent Balojasthan at this at this
point in time. If the US gets involved
in Balojasthan in the Baluchasthan
region as they're going to be because
they're interested in raw earth in rare
earth minerals and also in uh the oil
and gas sector in that case the US will
ensure that the BA the Bajjasthan
liberation army is crushed
right the US
doesn't care about human rights freedom
democracy it cares about its interests
and wherever where wherever it's
relevant it will preach human rights and
democracy and blah blah blah as a as a
stick to beat nations with but that's
just a stick. So independent Baljasthan
even without US support it's not
possible because the Pakistani military
is too powerful and with this new
scenario that the US is getting involved
in Pakistan in in a very big way there's
no chance of an independent Balojasthan
anytime soon.
Team talks Dharma says when Netanyahu
spoke 95% of the leaders left. What does
this indicate? Is this a play or acting
or European leaders truly believe in
Palestine?
Um what is what does this indicate?
It indicates that a lot of these
European leaders see if you look at the
European countries today, they have
significant Islamic populations now,
right? And their populations, even the
non-Islamic populations, non-immigrant
population, the the native populations,
they have been brainwashed and
indoctrinated by this left-leaning
education system. So they all believe
that Pakistan sorry yeah
Pak Palestine is a just cause that
Israel is a super oppressive country
that is oppressing the the poor hapless
uh peaceloving Palestinians.
So the people believe it and and the
immigrants the Islamic immigrants
obviously will support Palestine that
they will give an unconditional support
to the Palestinian cause.
So if you want to stay relevant as a
politician in that climate, you've got
to support Palestine. And of course,
see, we also know that EU, the EU
nations, uh they essentially are vasals
of the US. So if you want to sometimes
poke the master, you can do it by poking
the master's best friend, which is
Israel. So because of these the the
combination of all these factors that's
why all these leaders especially EU
leaders and whoever else they walked out
when Netanyahu spoke and left him with
an empty empty hall essentially cause
significantly emptier than what it
should have been not entirely empty of
course but that's what they did so yeah
that I I in my opinion that was
completely wrong if you if you're going
to sit and listen to a terrorist
al-Qaeda head head cutter stand and give
view of lecture. Well, I think Isra is
Israel is a far better nation than than
anything that al-Qaeda represents,
right? Israel is way better than that.
Um, so anyway, so so that's why this
happened and I completely disagree with
that.
Rahul says, "Are Chinese games like
Ginshin a part of their soft power? I've
seen kids develop a soft spot for China
just like Japan after producing animes,
etc." Well, of course. Of course.
If you enjoy a Chinese game, you're
going to like China, aren't you? The
Chinese produced this game that I'm so
attached to that I that gives me so much
emotional support and gives me so much
pleasure and joy in life and happiness.
So, the Chinese produce this obviously
I'm going to like China. If I enjoy
watching anime, Japanese anime, it has
given me so many countless hours of
happiness, right, that other people
can't provide, then obviously I'm going
to have a soft corner towards Japan. So
now the Chinese are also doing that.
They also producing high quality games
or whatever. I don't know genshin I have
no idea about this but clearly they are
also doing that. So this obviously is a
component of soft power
and it makes people unknowingly develop
positive sentiments towards you right
and India has the world's biggest pool
of video game developers and anime
people and CGI developers and whatnot
but we produce nothing we simply work
for other countries that's the problem
with India that's the
Pawan ga says master's ph from IIT
should I try try for page now is this a
geopolitical question sir I see once I
start taking questions like this it's
going to devolve into ask me anything
like no topic and then the people the
audience who has come to
come to understand geopolitics they will
be betrayed by me uh what is master's ph
first of all ph what is PH
I'm I'm not sure sir I see I cannot
answer this question un unless I know
you personally and I know your
background and I know your hopes and
dreams and aspirations without that I
can't really answer this question so I'm
going to pass on it I apologize Kiran
Mur well when did sir come here sir you
are one of our great wicket keepers
Kiran Mur
I'm sure it's a different one but anyway
uh just a joke uh in one of your videos
you said that if India reaches $10
trillion economy We could change our
education system but why are we but why
not at 7 or 8 trillion economy? I think
we can change our education system right
now. I don't think I would have said
that at 10 trillion we will change our
education system. No no no we can change
it right now. We can start the process
right now. Why do we have to wait for 10
trillion? We are what 4 something
trillion right now. We can do it. We can
start the steps. It's a 20 25 year
30-year process. We should start the
steps right now. It doesn't cost a lot
of money. It obviously is a logistical
thing. It's it'll take time. But that's
why we have to start as early as
possible. We don't have to wait for us
becoming a $10 trillion economy. That'll
be too late. That'll be too late to
start the process. We have to start it
right now.
This is a ticking time bomb. We can't
wait. The education system has to be
reformed. And the reforms have to start
not. They should have started 10 years
ago but anyway start now right we don't
need to wait for $10 trillion economy
I'm not sure I I would have ever said
that I would have said something else
about $10 trillion economy that
something else could happen I have said
that India will be a different kind of
beast once it is at a 10 trillion
economy mark it'll behave differently
that's what I I've said I've not said
that we need to start something at $10
trillion economy once we reach that
stage no no the education system reforms
need needed need to have started they
should started 10 years ago but even now
we're not starting it. That's the
tragedy of India. That's your great
leadership for you. They can't see the
problems and what what these issues are
how these issues are going to compound
in the coming years. Whatever problems
we have right now in 10 years, it's
going to be compounded because of the
rotten education system. That's the
problem.
Abu Sig says, why are we treated more
harshly than China by the US? China is a
$18 trillion economy. We are a $4
trillion economy. See the size
difference? So obviously
listen, let's say you go to the zoo, you
see a gigantic tiger. Are you going to
are you going to taunt the tiger? But if
you see a little cat, you will be more
likely to taunt the cat. Right? That's
how it goes, sir. Size matters. Size
matters. Understand that.
Wun Baj says, "Why is Pakist
Bangladesh's military weaker than
Pakistan despite higher GDP? What
factors explain this gap?" Well, that's
an interesting question. Let's let's
quickly take a look at what's the
difference between the two GDPs. Uh
Bangladesh
versus Pakistan
GDP
higher nominal GDP than Pakistan
comparison. Okay. GDP comparison
Bangladesh is 450 and Pakistan is 373.
Bangladesh per capita comp comparison
Bangladesh is way ahead of Pakistan
right interesting so Bangladesh is way
ahead of Pakistan but uh it's but
Pakistan obviously has a well
comparatively more powerful military
than Bangladesh I think Bangladesh
I have no idea I've never thought about
I don't spend time thinking about
Pakistan and Bangladesh that much but
definitely not about Bangladesh
Uh no no no disrespect to Bangladesh
they yeah but I don't really think about
Bangladesh that much. Uh what what
factors could explain this gap?
It's a really interesting question. I
mean you've got a bigger GDP than
Pakistan but Pakistan is more powerful
than you militarily. What what I what is
wrong with Bangladesh? Do you people
have no ambition?
In case any Bangladesh are watching,
please go to your your what what's his
name? Yunus Muhammad Inus and tell him
that at least bring us above Pakistan in
terms of military capabilities,
right? I don't know maybe it's a lack of
ambition
or maybe it's a lack of threat
perception. Okay, let's let's
reformulate reformulate the thing. See
Pakistan
it says that its biggest threat
existential threat is India and we have
to maintain a powerful military because
India otherwise will come and eat us
alive. That's what the Pakistani
military that's the story they have been
selling their public in order to ensure
that they remain legitimate in the eyes
of the public because the moment the
legitimacy goes the Pakistani public
which is like starving zombies will come
and eat the Pakistani military alive no
matter what the Pakistani military does
with their weapons. So the Pakistani
military has to sell this fake idea that
India is an existential threat which
also allows them to spend way more than
they should have spent on military
because if if there's no threat in your
neighborhood you don't have to spend
that much on a milit on the military. So
that's why Pakistan has been spending
way more than they should have spent on
the military and which is why they have
a more powerful military. Bangladesh is
I think it's not about lack of ambition.
It's about the fact that Bangladesh is a
more realistic country. They know that
India is not going to turn up tomorrow
morning on their doorstep and you know
invade. India has no no intention of
invading Bangladesh.
We want our Bangladeshi infiltrators the
the ones who are squatting on our
territory to go back to Bangladesh.
That's all we want. If we invariant
capture Bangladesh, we will have to deal
with millions more. Hundreds of millions
more. Imagine, imagine the nightmare
several million more Bangladeshes to
deal with
several hundred million more. India
doesn't want that. We want Bangladesh to
stay where it is.
Please stay a separate sovereign nation.
Please. So Bangladesh knows that that
they don't don't face any threat from
India neither from Burma. And that's why
they don't really need to develop
gigantically powerful armed um you know
military. I think that's the real reason
they are more
more realistic than Pakistan.
That's the reason I suppose. Rahul says
India seems to have found some gas in
the undermines. If the US doesn't force
India into selling oil and gas only in
exchange of US dollars, could it be the
end of the USD? It's it's too early to
talk about the end of the USD. We have
found some some natural gas in the
undermands. Okay, good. Fantastic. How
much? What's the quantity? What's how
big is the reservoir?
And gas isn't enough. We need liquid
petroleum. That's what we need. We need
we need it in in large quantities.
I'm sure it is there, but we have to go
and drill drill drill and find it,
right? And then we have to
operationalize the production.
So, a little bit of gas we found. It's
it's very encouraging. I'm I'm I'm glad
this was announced. I think yesterday
day before whenever it was announced and
the US has no business trying to force
us into anything. H
the US can give us a suggestion that you
know maybe it will be nice if you sell
it in USD and then we can decide. But
that is putting I mean that's that's
going too far down the down the road.
We we are a sovereign nation. We are one
of the five only genuinely sovereign
nations and the US will not be able to
arm twist us into anything.
Um so it's it's a very preliminary
announcement. Let's wait. I think it'll
take time before we make any major
discoveries of oil. Gas isn't that gas
is also important but not as important
as oil. So let's wait and watch.
Only once we make a major discovery of
oil can we even start having the
conversation of what currency to sell it
in and then we can perhaps talk about
perhaps the end of the USD at some point
in time in the future. It is too early
for that.
Adita says we know that history tends to
repeat itself. I'm glad we know that sir
knowing this what potential reasons
could cause the most powerful empire in
today's age hypothetically fall apart.
See historically empires when they fall
usually the causes lie within.
Usually it's because they become too
overconfident and they start taking
their imperial responsibilities too
lightly. They don't spend they don't
they don't invest enough in the
maintenance of the instruments of power
and uh the political leadership becomes
weaker. You have you know new leaders
are less capable than previous leaders
that sort of thing and that's why
cumulatively all these things add up and
eventually empire starts slowly
crumbling. Sometimes they crumble
crumble in one day sometimes they
crumble over the over a period of 50 to
100 years depends.
So uh lots of different causes. Now if
you want to apply that to the US
obviously you're talking about the US
here. So yeah. So uh
what could be the causes that could
eventually lead to the decline of the US
empire? Well, right now I don't see any
of that. See, they are not taking their
imperial responsibilities lightly. They
are maintaining their global power
projection capabilities.
There are 700 plus extr territorial
military bases spread across the world.
They are maintaining those. They are not
withdrawing from any of those. They're
not shutting down any bases. They're
ensuring that they're all well supplied.
They actually want more bases. They want
Bagram now. So you see they're expanding
their territorial their their power
projection footprint. So I don't see
that happening, right? That they're
taking their duties lightly, imperial
responsibilities lightly. Secondly,
we don't know who really leads the US.
Do you think Trump leads the US? Do you
think Joe Biden was leading the US? The
US president is simply a figurehead.
It's someone whose job is to draw all
the attention away from where the real
power lies.
Okay. So, we don't really know the
quality of the leadership who's really
leading the US. So, I can't say that's
one of the things the Anglo-Saxons have
done very well. They've hidden their
instruments of power. They've hidden
where the real leadership lies.
But if that leadership deteriorates,
right, if they no longer take good
decisions, if they are no longer
unified, whatever, then that will cause
problems. So these are some of the
problems that could eventually cause the
the the the decline and eventual
disintegration of the world's most
powerful empire today.
Rohill says, "With the US military
spread worldwide, could it eventually
become unmanageable and lead to the
decline of the US hgemony?" No, I don't
think so. No. Um, they are managing it
very well, right? There's no issue right
now. No issue whatsoever. Do you see any
chaos anywhere? Do you see any issues
with logistics, any issues with whatever
leadership? Nothing. It's being managed
really well. So from 1945 all the way
until today, which is almost like 80
years, they've done a tremendous job at
slowly expanding this network of
military bases. And what I think it will
be unman unmanageable the moment it
reaches Mars I think they'll be able to
manage moon also if they have military
bases on the moon in the next 30 40
years once it reaches Mars it will
become unmanageable the earth they can
deal with that's how powerful the US
military spread is and and their
capabilities are
geopolitical says how do you see the
future of India US defense ties there's
no future it's for there's no India
India US defense ties
what what do they expect now we're going
to buy some F-35s we will buy nothing
from the US you can't trust the US India
cannot trust the US that whatever little
trust existed is gone after operation
Sindur and the US support for Pakistan
and after this operation sindur ended or
paused the US support for Pakistan has
only intensified
how can India ever trust the US can
there is no future for India US defense
ties I think even the quad will die a
slow quiet death
I'm telling you right now the quad is
also done the quadrilateral dialogue
whatever it is the US India Japan and
Australia even that is finished okay it
it I don't see any more quad related
developments happening now
MK says why can't China and India just
increase their nuclear arsenal to
increase their comprehensive national
power. Is the deep state a boon or a
bane for the US and its people? Two
questions.
I'm sure China and India can increase
their nuclear arsenal to increase their
CNP. I'm sure we I'm sure they can do
it. Who knows? They may be doing it.
See, I I'll show you. See
um list of nuclear states with um
list of
of nuclear
weapons by country. Okay, let's do this.
Okay, so let's see what Wikipedia has to
say. Okay, so here we have it. Why is
the US on top? Why? Oh, because
apparently they know exactly how many
have been deployed. How does Wikipedia
know exactly how many nuclear weapons a
country has and how many are deployed?
How do they know this? Oh, because CRI
has said it.
Yeah, because the the Russians are going
to go and tell CRI exactly how many we
have and how many we have deployed.
Yeah, right. Very nice. So according to
these open-source uh rankings and
listings, India has 180, Pakistan has
170 and uh China has 600, France has
290, but China has only deployed 24.
India has deployed zero.
Okay, how do they know all these things?
How do they know that India only has
these many? How do they know how many
India is deployed? How many China is
deployed? These this is all these are
all fairy tales they're selling you. You
think China is going to go and tell
these people how many nuclear weapons we
actually have, how many warheads we
have, how many are deployed, how many
are disassembled and so on. You think
China will tell anybody? You think
Russia will tell the West all these
things? You think India is going to go
and tell these people?
This is all nonsense. We don't know how
many nuclear weapons each country has.
This story that India has 180, I don't
believe it one moment.
India has enough file material for
several thousand nuclear warheads by the
way. So,
so it's entirely possible for us to do
it, but we don't announce it to the
world, right? That's how it goes.
A Rahul says, "What in what ways can a
tuba like eruption impact geopolitics?"
Oh, well, a touba like volcanic eruption
will have seismic effects on
geopolitics. What's a Toba like volcanic
eruption? The Toba super volcano
eruption happened about 74,000 years ago
and it caused what's called a volcanic
winter which is the same thing as a
nuclear winter. The world went dark for
about 5 to 10 years. A decade roughly.
There was no sunlight for a decade
roughly. Roughly a decade. Because of
that plants died because of the death of
plants. The
planteat animals died. Because of that
flesheating animals died and because of
all these things humans had to scramble
to survive and humans survived in the
Indian subcontinent. We know that
because we have evidence in Jalapuram.
We have evidence in Madhya Pradesh or
wherever two three sites. We have
evidence in India that Indians survived
the super volcano eruption
but they would have survived just barely
by scattering and dispersing over wide
amounts of territory. Otherwise you die
because there's no resources available.
There's no food available. So if a Toba
like super vilo eruption happens today,
it's going to cause a catastrophic
decline in the world's population, human
population and and animal and plant
population, right? It could cause the
the disappearance of entire species of
animals.
The human population may fall by more
than 90%, it's going to be a disaster.
So what geopolitics will be we'll be
scrambling just to stay alive if this
happens. There's going to be no
geopolitics left and then after 10 years
whatever survives then we will restart
the world.
Abishek Singh says after operation
Sindur it looks like Pakistani expiry
date is extended because the US is now
propping up Pakistan. So as long as the
US does that there's nothing India can
do about it. Right? So that's correct.
Pakistan's expiry date is currently
extended because of US support.
feels strong. Man says, "Have you played
Age of Empire of Civilization 6 games?"
No, I haven't. I haven't. Never had the
time to do that.
Al says, "I don't see India proactively
planning for natural disasters when it's
a fact that disasters and diseases have
destroyed more civilizations than wars."
You see, India is not a disasterprone
area.
Northern India, far north, Himalayas,
yeah, we have earthquakes. Keeps
happening. It's not going to destroy
India civilization. The west of India,
the Kach region, yeah, sure we have
earthquakes once in every few decades.
It's not going to destroy India
civilization. There are other parts of
India which are kind of seism
seismically active like the far east of
India, the foothills of the Himalayas,
the Manipur region etc. But over there
once again the earthquakes aren't that
those that powerful. And once again even
if Manipur is destroyed is it going to
destroy India civilization? No, it's
not. Uh what else do we do? We have any
major volcanoes? We have a couple of
volcanoes in the Arnamans, Narakandam
and Baron Island. I can think of two
right now. Are they going to destroy
India civilization? No. We have flash
floods and all in Uttarakhand whatever.
Is it going to destroy India
civilization? No. We have nothing that
can actually destroy India civilization.
We have typhoons. What cyclones that
happen every year or something? Are they
going to destroy India civilization?
They're not going to do it. Do we have
tsunamis? Maybe once in a 100 years. Can
it destroy India civilization? It can't.
There is nothing
that can destroy India civilization. No
natural disaster.
See Japan for example, it is prone to 9
plus earthquakes on the on the RTOR
scale. You have earthquakes all the
time. That's why they have to adapt.
They have had to adapt their entire
lifestyle
to account for the possibility of very
major earthquakes. So the earthquakes in
Japan and the volcanism in Japan is such
that it can indeed destroy Japan
civilization which is why the Japanese
society has had to adapt.
So Japan is is located smack bang in the
ring of fire. So that's why Japan has
had to adapt and that's why they they
have a different kind of society than
what we have over here. We are blessed
by the gods in the Indian subcontinent.
There's nothing that can actually
destroy India civilization. No natural
disaster can. You will have floods,
you'll have earthquakes, you'll have
whatever from time to time. It will
cause pain and suffering from various in
certain parts of India. Yeah. And uh
you'll have cyclones that come that that
cause problems once in a while. But none
of this is going to destroy India
civilization. Nothing. Which is why
India doesn't plan proactively perhaps.
I mean we do have cyclone management
systems now. We have early warning
systems which is why we have so few
deaths now. So once again I would not
entirely agree that we don't proactively
plan. If you look at the coasts of
Odisha and Kerala and whatnot now we
have advanced warning systems for
cyclones.
We hardly hear of of any disastrous
death tolls from cyclones anymore. If if
if five people die, it becomes national
news now in a cyclone. Right. We have
Assam. Yeah. That's another problem. The
Brahmaputra floods every year. people
are kind of used to it and nothing is
done about it for some reason. I don't
know maybe maybe something has been done
but it happens anyway every year but
once again it can't destroy India's
civilization. So I think that we are
taking steps and measures to certain
extent to plan for these things but uh
the fact is that none of these natural
disasters can actually destroy India's
civilization. So we are blessed by the
gods in that manner. Maybe it has made
us complacent, you know. Who knows?
Dave says, "We are waiting for your
channel on Aratai." Okay, Aratai. I
still haven't installed Aratai. So maybe
I'll have to do that. I should do it to
well to support the Swadeshi cause. I
hope it is a good enough app. I'm sure
it is. Shidrabu is doing it. So it must
be good. And then should we have a
channel on it? See the problem is that I
don't I don't mind getting on Aratai and
using it as my messenger. The problem
with managing a channel is that you have
to have moderators and you need to look
into it all the time. And I'm a very
busy person. I'm busy every day. I'm
writing. I'm doing something or the
other. I don't have the time to manage a
channel like a channel on Aratai, you
know, moderation and all that. I don't
have the time to be present and interact
with people every day because I'm so
busy. So, I I really appreciate the fact
that you you want me to do this, but
I'll have to be very I'll have to think
about it properly before I I venture
into that domain because in the past
I've had a Discord channel once or twice
and it it ran ran ran out of control. I
had to end it. I think I have a Telegram
group somewhere. I'm not sure. So, you
know, it's it's worthwhile. It's
valuable only if I can spend time on it
and I can actually be be present over
there. So I I'll I'll consider this
seriously but I can't promise anything
at this stage. All right.
Rahul says isn't I inr Indian rupee
depreciation a good thing for it depends
on whether you are an exporter or an
importer. If you're an exporter and you
are receiving foreign exchange
then you can earn a lot of rupees
through that. But if you're an importer,
so it depends on various things. It it's
not necessarily a good thing or a bad
thing. It depends on what your specific
situation and circumstances is. So China
for example has ensured that its
currency remains undervalued and that
has helped them a lot because they are a
major exporter. So if India becomes a
major exporter, it may be good if
India's currency remains undervalued.
Rohanja says why Sweden Sweden innovates
but India has failed to do the same
because of the Indian system which
discourages innovation. Think of the
time you were in school. Did your
teachers ever encourage your in you to
innovate? Did they ever encourage you to
ask questions? Did they ever encourage
you to do something different from
everybody else? No. They will not
tolerate that. They will squash that in
the bud. If you ever dare to do anything
different from everybody else,
then the teachers will punish you for
that. You have to understand the system
is such that Indians are brainwashed
like sheep. And even beyond school,
Indian society discourages people from
innovating. You try to do something
different from everybody else, whole
society stands up in front of you,
right? These are these are problems that
we face in India. Dish says, how do we
completely eradicate internal enemies?
Well, there are certain there are
various models that exist from world
history. I will not name any of the
models, but there are models that exist
from world history. It has been done by
various uh world powers in the past in a
variety of ways but I shall not name
those world powers because it would be
inappropriate to do so. It is entirely
possible to to eradicate internal and to
eradicate internal enemies. There are
multiple ways of doing it but it is not
um suitable to discuss those things
here. Ritipar asks a question in Hindi.
Well, okay. I'm not that good in Hindi.
I I'm slow. Taiwan 2030
the CCP
or exp on expansionist mode and USA
officially
YouTube
block English oh really is that why I
don't know why okay so you're asking
what okay
maybe there are some keywords that
you're some some terms you're using that
you YouTube is blocking. Okay, whatever.
Okay. No, no, I understand totally why
you're asking in Hindi. So, uh will so
Taiwan 2030 if if Taiwan falls by 2030,
what are the the the pros and cons for
India and the world and will China go
will the Chinese Communist Party go into
expansionist mode and will the US fall
because of this? Okay,
so let's say Taiwan falls by 2030. What
are the pros and cons of the world?
First of all, let's understand what will
be the effects. Taiwan will not fall
just like that. Everything on Taiwan
will be destroyed. All the industries,
all the, you know, TSMC, whatever. China
will inherit a destroyed island with
some people on it. But no industry is
nothing. So, it will be a hollow victory
for China if China actually acquires
Taiwan.
But yeah, it will be the breaking of one
of the island chains. So,
China will feel that, you know, they've
been able to score a major victory over
the US. Uh, will that make China go into
expan expansionist mode visav other
countries? I'm not sure about that.
I'm not really sure about that. Um,
because see other countries have it's
it's it's a totally different set of
parameters that you have right between
China and India, China and Japan, China
and South Korea. It's a total different
set of risks for China in each stage. So
I'm not sure China will go into
expansionist mode just because they have
acquired Taiwan. But they will become
definitely more
confident. And will the fall of Taiwan
cause the patan the fall of the US? I'm
not sure about that. I think Taiwan will
fall only if the US feels that it's time
to let Taiwan go. If the US feels that
that Taiwan is still important to us,
they will not allow Taiwan to fall.
Right? Uh so I don't think it's going to
cause the fall of the US but it will
certainly make China much more confident
even if they acquire a a shell of an
island with nothing nothing of value on
it.
Raal says how can I avoid adopting your
bias by watching more of your content? I
notice I start thinking in your line
instead of de developing my own
thoughts. That's always a problem if you
watch too much of something. Okay, let
me be very clear about this. If the the
best thing to do is to if you are
consuming content, you should consume
content not only from one source but
from multiple sources and not just from
one kind of medium, not just YouTube,
you should also read. Reading is very
important, right? So if you have that
sort of consumption pattern
then it is more difficult for you to go
along one line of thinking on uh you
know to start thinking along the lines
of one specific person and even more
important you should if you really are
worried about this you should write
every day spend 30 minutes writing about
any topic what do I think about this
topic and why do I think that way just
write it down because writing clarifies
and crystallizes your thoughts And it
forces you to think independently.
So let's say you feel that you are you
you're beginning to think like me for
example. So take a piece of paper, take
a pencil, pen, whatever. Give yourself
30 minutes and write what do I think
about so and so topic about so and so
issue. Why do I think that way? Right?
And what other ways could I think? What
are the other considerations, other
perspectives I can think about? And what
are their pros and cons? and try and
convince yourself
in this manner which is the best way of
which is the best you know line of
thought. So that's what you should do.
Don't only consume content from one
channel. I mean even though I would very
much want you want everyone to consume
only my content but I'm telling you
truthfully you should not
watch as many diverse sources as
possible and read and more importantly
write writing even 30 minutes a day just
writing about anything. It will force
you to think independently. So that's
what you have to do. If you really want
to develop your own way of thinking,
your own line of thought, you must
write. It's not enough to just sit and
think for half an hour. That's not
enough. Write. Writing will force you to
think clearly.
Right. Okay. Ab says Isra specifically
BB refused to put sanctions on Russia
and supply weapons to UA. What's UA?
Ukraine. Ukraine. Is it because Israel
is sovereign? BB is a strong leader.
Um, Israel has refused to put sanctions
on Russia and supply weapons to the to
Ukraine. Is it because Israel is
sovereign? See, Israel and Russia have
their own relationship.
There's a very large number of Russian
Jews who live in Israel, right?
That is one factor. The other factor is
that Israel is no one's vasal.
You see whenever I discuss Israel I see
two kinds of comments. If there are 100
comments 50 comments will be saying that
Israel is America's vasal. The other 50
comments will be saying the US is
Israel's vasal.
I will just say this that Israel is
completely sovereign. Israel doesn't
have doesn't feel that it has to go
along with one with somebody's line of
thinking. It doesn't have to take uh
take take part in someone's geopolitical
stance. It can act on its own. and
Israel and see even even Zelinsky is
Jewish, isn't he? So that's also another
interesting fact. But see the thing is
that Israel is a sovereign nation.
That's the most important thing we have
to understand. I I used to say there are
four sovereign nations in 2024. I have
revised that it is five because I had
not thought clearly about Israel. Israel
is definitely 100% genuinely sovereign.
It's one of the only five sovereign
nations in the world and as such it can
decide its own course of action. It
doesn't have to go along with what what
the US wants.
So that's just what it is.
B Mandav says why is India behind build
in building a motor engine? A motor
engine
compared to other countries also. What
are your views on the flower engine
which is made in India? I am not aware
of any flower engine. Let's Google it.
Flower engine. What is that? Let's find
out. Flower
engine
India. Really? What's a flower engine?
I don't see anything. A flower engine
made in India. Really? Made in India.
There is no flower engine. What is this?
Uh there are flower engine flower
gifting. Haridam artificial flowers
India Mart. Okay. I have no idea what
this flower engine is. So I don't know.
Okay. I'm sorry. Um I I'm not sure what
this flower engine is, sir. I apologize
for that. But why is when you're talking
about motor engine, are you talking
about motor vehicles, car engines,
you're talking about truck engines?
You're talking about ship engines.
You're talking about jet engines.
Let's say you're talking about generic
just engines. Well, it's because we
because we we don't do research and
development. We don't do R&D. We just
want to acquire stuff from from abroad.
Foreign say we'll take it. We'll buy it
from foreign, right? Why make it
ourselves? Why why reinvent the wheel?
We can just import it. We pay some
money. We get a high quality engine. Why
do we have to start this process all
over again?
Laziness.
Indian entrepreneurs just want to make
money. They don't want they don't think
long term.
They don't think long term. They want to
make money right now.
Big issue. Uh yeah. So that's
essentially what plagues India. Indian
entrepreneurs. If you look at IT for
example, it has always been the
arbitrage model. They will we have such
talented software engineers in this
country. But do you see any IT Indian IT
company developing any software products
of his own? No. It'll simply work for
other foreign country companies
who have their own products and we will
maintain those products. We'll develop
the products for them. But we will not
develop anything ourselves because that
is slightly more risky. Right? That's
higher there's higher risk in that. Do
you see Indian IT firms or Indian
companies uh you know when they talk
about swadeshi apps h apps apps as in
cell phone apps or whatever
what does it mean for an for an app to
be Indian totally Indian does it mean
that Indians have developed it and
Indians will profit from it is that all
but let's say you have I am not talking
about any specific app here I'm just
saying let's say you have some app in
which you have to login sign up all that
and your data will be stored somewhere.
Where is the data being stored? Is the
data also being stored in India or is it
being stored on Amazon's web server
somewhere AWS or something else? If it
is being stored in the US, is it really
an Indian app? That also you have to
think about. So there are all these
things that we have to consider. The
problem is that Indian entrepreneurs,
they are still very risk averse. big
Indian companies, big Indian IT firms,
big whatever the firms, they have sought
to make as much money as possible, as
quickly as possible and keep that model
going as long as it can go and they
don't invest in R&D. They simply don't
invest in R&D, which is why nothing
happens in India, right? That's the
issue.
Swastik Mahesh says, what actions should
India take against foreign funded
industrial scale conversions? We should
simply stop the flow of money.
If money has to flow into India, it has
to come through the FC channels, right?
Why are we still allowing this? Why are
we allowing this? Why? Why? I don't get
it. Why is it some fundamental human
right that others that foreigners have
the right to convert people in India?
Now they have set up Indian Indian um
proxies obviously who do the
conversions. So it's no longer
foreigners who come to India and and
convert people. It's Indians themselves
who are converted and who will convert
more. But all of these activities need a
tremendous amount of money.
Much of the money comes from abroad. End
that. Right? Why are we not ending that?
Maybe there is pressure not to end that.
You see, it's it's high time we end all
all of these things because anyway the
US India relationship isn't great now.
How much more will we will we tolerate?
The money comes from the US. By the way,
iss777
says BU has started using its in-house
chips for AI. Also, China is producing
electricity by solar at a much less
cost, which is a big advantage for its
super clusters.
How big is their military advantage?
Okay, let's deconstruct what you're
saying. BU has started started using
in-house chips for AI. Yes, China is
producing chips now at pretty good
quality chips, AI chips.
They're just a few steps behind Nvidia,
right?
Because they have been investing in in
chip development technology and all that
for a very long time, for at least a
couple of decades. We are starting now.
So, they have a 20 year at least minimum
20 year advantage over us. That's number
one. China is producing electricity at
by solar at a much less cost much less
cost. So no one's stopping India from
innovating in solar. We also have huge
areas of the country which are barren
like the Thar desert and other parts of
India construct gigantic solar farms and
that also will be an advantage for our
superclusters right okay so that's the
deal so how big is their military
advantage compared to India significant
obviously first of all we don't produce
chips of that quality right now it'll
take us a decade to reach that quality
of chips but anyway we have we are
starting the process now which is great
so in a decade we'll be at a good at a
good stage in um chip quality Even now
we produce we we are beginning to
produce decent chips. Not bad. So at
least I'm glad that is happening. It's
not like we are not doing anything. We
are doing something. Uh so if you talk
about it's China's military advantage
over India or over the US I'm I'm
suppose I'm supposing India in that case
they have a significant advantage
because they have adopted AI at a very
very very big scale.
uh they have this facial recognition
technology that has been u deployed in
China for many years. It's very
powerful, very sophisticated and they
will have similar technologies that will
be used in the military domain. So I
think China has a significant military
advantage over India when it comes to
the adoption of AI and the fact that
China produces higher quality chips than
India's India and possibly more more
electricity as well. So overall bigger
advantage significant advantage over
India.
Okay. CJ Kos says uh a recent
recent progress
PRG progress I suppose from Israel
happening in Cyprus.
Is this a second step of Zionist
expansionism?
A domin domination plan in Mediterranean
and next. Is it bad for India? A recent
what is happening? P RGS from Israel.
Recent progress
from Israel happening in
Cyprus.
Uh let me Google this. I'm not sure what
you're saying, sir. Let me try and
Google this. Israel. Cypress. Really?
Israel has an embassy. What is Israel
aiming for in Cyprus? Israel Greek
criate alliance
weapons bases settlers Greek administers
center for Jewish impact.
Um Cyprus getting Israeli defense
something or the other. This is 18th
September which is pretty recent. Let's
see what this says.
Israeli defense system. Okay.
Israeli defense system.
Okay. That's good for for Cypress, I
would say. Good for Cypress. What else
do we have? What other news do we have?
Israeli linked arament of Greek Greek
criates. Okay. Israel is arming Greek
criates. Outstanding. I I good for good
for the Greek criates, I would say. Uh
bases of Cypress globally, Reno. What is
that? After barak system. Oh, the barak
system that we also use. Okay. Why is
Turkey losing its sleep?
and so on and so forth.
Okay. So, Israel is is uh enhancing its
cooperation with with Cypress, with
Greek Cyprus. Is this a step in Zionist
expansionism? I'm not sure about that.
I'm not sure. Uh dominion domination
plan in the Mediterranean. Let's take a
look at the map to see the Mediterranean
region and then we can perhaps uh
discuss this. Does Israel really seek to
dominate the whole Mediterranean and
expand into Cyprus? Let's see.
So in case people aren't aware, this is
Cypress. Okay, this island it is
partitioned uh northern Cypress
is held by by Turkey. Southern Cypress
is uh is Greek majority and there's a
significant uh you know this place which
is uh no man's land essentially. So it's
a part de def factor partitioned country
and over here we have Israel which is
not far at all from Cypress as you can
see from southern Cyprus. If you want to
see the distance between uh between for
example Hifa and Limasol
it's barely 278 km so not far at all. Uh
so Israel seems to be um intensifying or
expanding its military and other
cooperation with uh the Greek criates
which obviously will concern Turkey.
Does this mean that there is
an intention to expand into Cyprus? I
don't think so. Is this is this does it
signify that Israel has a plan to
dominate the Mediterranean? I think
Israel has a plan to ensure that nobody
else dominates the Mediterranean at its
expense. So it will take care of its uh
of its interests in the Mediterranean.
If Turkey is expanding its footprint for
example in North Africa etc. then Israel
will make sure that it expands its
footprint in other other part of the
Mediterranean that makes sense for
Israel to do. So I don't see this as a
Zionist expansionism. I don't see this
as a great nefarious domination plan by
Israel in the Mediterranean. They are
simply looking out for their national
interest. And uh you see what you do is
whoever is friendly to you, you ensure
that you have better relations with
them. So Israel is doing the same thing
and I don't blame them for it. They are
doing whatever it takes to take care of
their interests as we should also do.
Deepankar Deori says, "What do you make
of the recent hate on social media like
X against India and Indians? Is it
organic or sponsored by some other
country like China, Pakistan, US?" This
is not recent. I have been speaking
about this since 2022.
It all started in February 22. What
happened in February 22? On the 22nd of
February 2022,
Shar Vladimir Putin gi launched his
special military operation in Ukraine.
And the US and the West insisted that
India should participate in their
sanctions against Russia and we refused.
Not only did we refuse, we also amped up
ramped up our purchases of Russian oil
because they were now available to us at
a discount. Right? So once we started
doing that there was an outpouring
initially
of articles against India
on western media outlets like the
Guardian like the BBC like uh Deutsch
Chavella like uh the New York the
Washington Post New York Times whatever
they all started this outpouring of of
anti-India articles various think tanks
like Rand Corporation and various rank
Rand corporation minions ions all of
those. But then it started on social
media on on Twitter accounts. So I have
been speaking about this since 2022.
It's not recent at all. But then it's it
became common place on Twitter. Before
2022, there was no such thing like India
anti-India hatred on Twitter. But after
2022, it's by the end of the year, it
had become pretty common place. And it
looks like it is not really organic.
Maybe the Pakistanis took advantage,
maybe the Chinese took advantage of the
situation to to spread anti-India
messaging, to spread anti-India
um you know cliches or whatever you want
to call it, you know, anti-India memes,
tropes, whatever. And um it is well
known that that the Chinese use Twitter
as you know a battlefield. They have
millions and millions of bot accounts.
You will see the server farms where they
have, you know, I have books over here.
Yeah. They will have stacks of of cell
phones
in server farms. Millions of cell phones
each with one Twitter account and
they'll all be, you know,
programmatically putting out propaganda.
So, the Chinese do that. The Pakistanis
also are really good at this. India is
the one nation that doesn't participate
in these wars.
India has been very poor at propaganda.
India has been very poor at defending
itself. This is the big
fail of the government of India.
And now it looks like even the American
government may be behind this. So I am
pretty sure that all three governments
that you're that you are uh mentioning
over here, China, Pakistan, US, all
three are involved. probably initially
it was just the western media outlets
and think tanks that were that were
doing this then you had NAFO something
called NAFO NAFO those bought accounts
went after went went after India the
Ukrainian government started putting out
anti-India memes on Twitter something to
do with Makali that sort of thing once
uh then you have the Pakistanis and
Chinese getting into it and and
amplifying the hatred towards Indians
and uh now probably the Americans are
also behind this so there's this huge
wave of hatred towards Indians on social
media. That's that's how it has
happened.
Praul says happy navatri well happy
navatri to you praul and to everybody
else as well. I see IT companies losing
US clients citing cost reasons. I
suspect a bigger wave is coming our way.
What should our IT strategy be if the US
tariffs Indian IT? What can our IT
strategy be? Nothing.
Our IT companies haven't evolved. The
past 30 years they've been serving US
clients. they have no other clients.
Okay, maybe they can try and diversify
to EU clients or whatever. The E the EU
doesn't have the kind of you know tech
support needs that the US has.
There's no strategy. The only strategy
is that Indian IT companies should start
now start developing products of their
own that can compete at global
standards. Without that they will sink.
I have been saying this for you are only
talking about this because the tariffs
are there right? I have been saying this
even before this. I have been saying
this for the past at least a year that
AI is going to kill India's IT firms. AI
can do the job of of junior programmers
today. Right? So if if I if I can if I
am a US tech company and I can get AI to
work for me at a certain price, why will
I pay more?
For example, I I believe that you can
get a pro plan of various AI systems at
$200 a month,
right? Whether it is Chart GP must be
the the pro professional plan, the most
advanced plan must be around $200,
right? And the same must go for Grock
and
Gemini and whatnot. So, you can get a
professional plan as an individual for
$200 a month.
Now if you look at the billing rates of
Indian companies, IT companies, the the
way they are billing American firms, it
will be minimum $20 an hour.
So for just one day, 8 hours for
example, that's $160 per person. The US
is is is spending
the US company spending per day per
person $160 at the lowest level.
Obviously, there's going to be billing
at higher levels also. So why not just
get get you know an AI subscription for
$200 a month you anyway spending $160 or
$200 per day per person so just get 10
AI clients who will work 24 by7 it's
much cheaper
so the only way Indian IT companies will
survive long term not short-term but
long term next 5 10 years is if they
develop highquality world-class products
of their own and compete at that level
not just provide services otherwise
They're going to all sink. There's no
other strategy. There's no other way
out.
Literally, Officer K says, "Some people
compare the US to the Roman Empire."
Well, okay. Do you believe that India
today deserves a comparison to the Rome
to the Moria Empire, or are we not there
yet? The US, if we compare it to the
Roman Empire, it's it's a comparison
that makes sense. The US is an empire,
but an empire at a much larger scale
than the Roman Empire.
I myself have made this comparison. So
yes, that is a valid comparison. It's a
legitimate comparison. Does India
believe today deserve a comparison with
the Moran Empire? Absolutely not. India
is nothing like the Moran Empire.
Today's India is nothing like the Morian
Empire. Today's India is a is a slightly
different version of the India that we
we had during the British Raj. The India
under British occupation. Today we are
under our own occupation. We have the
same system but we have our our own
people ruling over India the way the
British used to rule in a much inferior
manner.
We are not an empire. The Moran Empire
was very clear about its administration
about where the leadership lay.
You had one person at the top, the
emperor, the dictator. You never
questioned the emperor.
The entire subcontinent obeyed what the
emperor said and everything got done
whatever the emperor wanted. You do not
have corruption. You do not have lazy
corrupt officials. You do not have an
administrative service that was self-s
serving. You do not have other
institutions that served themselves or
served foreign powers allegedly
hypothetically right. You do not have
any of that during the Boran Empire. Is
India something that can be compared to
the Moran Empire? Absolutely not. It's a
very interesting comparison that you've
you know brought out over here. India
cannot be compared to the Moran Empire.
Absolutely not. There's nothing we can
there's no basis of comparison.
If India was comparable to the Moran
Empire today, it would be it would be a
very different entity, a much better
entity than what it is right now. I mean
look at India after today. Look at the
modern Empire of the time. the you know
India's temples are controlled by the
bureaucracy
and the government during the Moran era
did death happen absolutely not today
you have industrial scale uh conversions
religious conversions happening in India
would chupta Maria or Ashok tolerate
that do you know what he would do to
such people who would dare convert
Indians uh let's not discuss what he
would do right the education system in
India during the Morian era. Do you
think you can compare the quality of
that with what we have today? The rotten
education system today, the colonial
education system that we have today,
there is no comparison. You can't
compare today's India with the Morian
era. The Morian era was a time of way
higher standards than what we have
today.
Right? So yeah, great great comic.
vs says India denied American uh agro
and dairy products in the Indian market.
Could this be one among the several
reasons why Trump is putting so much
economic pressure on us? Is Trump
ensuring that he gets his job done
through the madman theory?
See, Trump wants a vasal. That's the
bottom line. He wants us to be the kind
of vasal that the EU is.
the EU. If you put all the EU nations
together and add them up, they are kind
of double the GDP of India
cumulatively speaking.
So India can only be compared with the
EU. So he wants India to be a vasal the
way the EU is and he wants a proper
vasal. So it will start with economic
vas but it will not end until there is
military vas also. That's what he wants.
And this entire matter of the the trade
deal and the dairy products and agro
parts is just to get a foot in the door
towards the step towards vasalage.
So the reason why Trump is putting so
much economic pressure on India is
because he wants India to bend to his
will to cave in and become a proper
vasal of the US. Today you had what
Howard Lutnik or whoever it was was
saying that India needs to be needs to
be dealt with in India what I'm not sure
what what exact words he used but he
they they essentially want India to
become an American vasal just like the
EU just like Japan just like South Korea
just like whatever else and because
they're not getting it because India
remains one of the five sovereign
nations that's why they are putting
economic pressure on us they're hoping
that this economic pressure will
eventually break
and they will get what they want a
complete unfettered access to the Indian
market they can dump any product they
want over here which means that all
India's manu India's manufacturing
sector all of the companies will die out
right and then once that happens when
India is completely controlled by the US
economically then they can start
installing American military bases on on
Indian soil the first stage is economic
the second stage is military that's the
end aim that they seek and because we
are not giving in because we are not
caving in that's why they are applying
pressure madman theory whatever it
doesn't matter he's not really a madman
he's a very shrewd man
okay
says many say Russia is polarizing the
American society my opinion I don't
think Russia has has the means to
polarize American society Russia is
simply a bogeyman that they the American
politicians use in order to make
political points so for example when
when you had the last US presidential
election
which is in what 2019 uh they accused
Trump of being in league with Russia and
they accused Russia of trying to
influence the course of the election by
by hacking or I'm not sure what so I
don't believe it at all I my opinion is
that Russia has nothing to do with any
of this and Russia is not not in a
position to influence American society
Russia doesn't have the techn
technological capability to do that.
ISX777
says Russia's median age is now 42. Big
worry for them. Oh yes, big worry for
them. Big worry for them. In 10 years
it's going to be a big worry for us also
because our TFR is now dropping below
three. Big problems ahead for India.
Rahul says the US citizens having guns
is their freedom but independent
countries apart from the west having
nukes is a crime. Oh yes. See
see there are two sets of rules in the
world. One set of rules applies to the
US and a different set of rules applies
to the world in different ways at
different times. That's how it goes. The
US is the most powerful and most
important country in the world.
So it has to live by a different set of
rules. You see, and those rules don't
apply to the rest of the world. So the
US can the citizens can have guns, they
can have machine guns, they can have
ARs, they can have AKs, they can have
M16s, the US can have several thousand
nuclear weapons, but no other country
should have any of these rights
obviously, right? The US is a different
different kind of country. It's a
superior country. They have rights that
other countries cannot have. Okay.
Ammon Patanya sir, thank you. Uh if the
US is arming the temporary nation
through Saudi, does that mean a low war
is loading soon and was that going to be
the end of that mercenary nation?
Mercenary mercenary nation is Pakistan.
If the US see right now the US has not
announced any weapons sales to Pakistan.
uh they have sent a few uh large scale
C130 or whatever transport aircraft to
Pakistan but they said that they were
simply sending uh you know relief
supplies to Pakistan. So as far as we
know the US has not announced any arms
sales to Pakistan officially
and maybe they can't do it because
Pakistan has this horrific track record
of being a terrorist nation and if they
sell arms to Pakistan openly officially
then their own citizens may
raise questions. So that's why this
Saudi Pakistan deal is a great way of
funneling weapons and cash and whatnot
into Pakistan through Saudi Arabia and
if it comes to light then you can simply
blame Saudi Arabia like you've blamed in
the past Saudi Arabia. Saudi Arabia has
always been the fall guy for the US. You
know they've always beaten Saudi Arabia
whenever it whenever they felt like. For
example, when the Kashog gi affair
happened, that uh journalist who
allegedly was murdered in the Saudi
embassy in Istanbul in Constantinople,
well, the US treated Saudi Arabia
Muhammad bin Salman like a pariah for a
few years, didn't they? Now everything
is back on track. Um so it is possible
that you may have announcements of Saudi
arms sales to Pakistan
not American arms sales but Saudi arm
sales but obviously the weapons will
come into Saudi Arabia from the US and
Saudi Arabia will say that we have some
surplus of weapons. So we are disposing
of it by by selling it to it to our
brotherly nation Pakistan. That's how it
will most likely be done. Nothing has
been announced thus far but I will not
be surprised if such announcements don't
happen soon. So in case we find that
Pakistan is going to receive you know
significant u sign significant uh you
know dispatches
uh deliveries of weapons and whatnot
from Saudi Arabia. It means that
that the the objective is to ensure that
Pakistan does not lose another Sindu
operation Synindhur like situation that
they are actually in a position to to
hit back hard at India. So if we start
seeing you know such developments like
Saudi Arabia is is selling weapons to
Pakistan, it may mean that a war could
happen soon. It may mean that yes the
objective for the US right now is that
Pakistan should not lose the next war to
India.
If operation sour had continued another
week, Pakistan would probably have been,
you know, broken into pieces. Very
likely the the operation Sundur was was
halted at the precise time when we took
out their air force when we neutralized
like 11 air bases in 20 minutes in 40
minutes. We created the runways. There
was no way the Pakistani aircraft could
could take off after that. Pakistan was
helpless at that point. their radar
systems were down
right so the Americans don't want the
situation to happen again so they will
supply Pakistan with with whatever they
need through Saudi Arabia and once the
news starts coming out it means that if
India doesn't take action soon Pakistan
may be in a situation where we can't
defeat them yeah so it could mean that a
war could be loading soon could it could
mean that yes
Amisha says Trump hints at greatness in
the Middle East and amid The 21point
Gaza plan. What's happening? And when is
the Maya chapter 2 coming? Okay. Trump
hints at greatness in the Middle East.
21point Gaza plan. I haven't seen that.
Let me check. Let me check. Let's
quickly Google this. 21 point Gaza plan.
Okay. Looks like something new. Trump
point point Gaza.
Okay, what's the deal? Trump's Gaza
peace plan revealed American 21point
plan for ending Gaza war. Let's take a
look at this. What is this all about? We
are opening the Times of Israel.
Vitkov proposal envisions all hostages
released in first 48 hours. Grants
amnesty to peace committing Hamas
members. encourages Gaza to remain,
Gazins to remain, sees US established
Palestinian, Israel, Palestinian
dialogue. 21point document shared by the
US with a handful of etc. countries,
etc., etc., etc. US proposal for ending
the war in Gaza. The decision to
explicitly encourage Palestinians to
remain in Gaza, caps off a major
evolution for Washington,
significant tain to the idea that
Netanyahu's far right, etc., etc. um
voluntary migration of gazins.
Okay. Okay. All of that exact sequencing
isn't specified. Requirements will make
likely the proposal diff difficult to
sell to Hamas.
The US plan is rather light on details
and so on. Okay. So, so that's the kind
of plan that Trump is proposing.
I think based on what I very quickly
saw, it's something that Hamas may not
accept.
But if they accept then things may go in
in a certain direction towards peace.
Yeah. Uh so we'll have to keep an eye on
this. I think it's too early to decide
what is happening, what direction things
are going going to go towards. Most
likely Hamas may not accept it. But if
they do accept it, then maybe Netanyahu
maybe not too happy because he would
ideally want all the Gazans to leave
Gaza, go to Indonesia or somewhere and
he can then redevelop Gaza into a
different part, a new part of Israel. So
yeah, I think it's too early to decide
what's happening. Uh Trump is trying to
perhaps negotiate some kind of peace,
but he will ensure that the peace is not
such that it will inconvenience Israel.
And if it is not something that will
inconvenience Israel then and and if it
is if it doesn't give too much to the
Palestinians and to into Hamas then
Hamas may not accept it because
otherwise Hamas loses legitimacy in the
eyes of its citizens Palestinians. And
so I think it's very complicated. It
will be an incredible achievement if
Trump is able to get the Israelis and
Palestinians to sit down together, shake
hands and sign some deal. If it happens,
he will certainly
be remembered as a great man if the if
the deal lasts, if the peace lasts. So,
I think we'll have to wait and watch.
Uh, Mirrors of Maya Chapter 2, I think,
should come out by next by the coming
weekend. Hopefully. Hopefully. See,
writing stories is is way more difficult
than than something I mean, let's say
you you are making samosas. You can make
samosas on demand, right? But writing a
story, it has to be different and
interesting and unique every time. It
can't be boring. So it it takes time and
I'm new at this especially writing
fiction. So it takes time. I'm hoping
it'll come out by by this coming
weekend. But let's see. Right. But
anyway, thank you so much. I thank you
for so much for for the review that you
left, reviews that you left. I really
appreciate that.
Rohit Singh says, "Big fan of your work,
sir." Thank you so much, Sat Rohit G.
Thank you.
Why are there so many videos on on X of
Americans fighting, looting or shouting
while getting arrested? Is it normal?
So, I was a few months ago
I was at a at a at an event, a private
event where you had some members of the
EU Parliament.
Okay.
And after a few drinks, they talk
better. I mean they they talk more
openly. So we were discussing all kinds
of things and uh I I said that you know
the way I see it I've been in the EU
I've been in the US. I've traveled I've
lived in various parts of the world. The
way I see it see it the EU and the US
are police states. And the gentleman I
was talking with he said you're right.
The EU is a police state. You see what
do I mean by that police state? It means
that if you remove the police force from
the streets that you're going to have
anarchy
in a short period of time and it's not
that much the case in the EU as compared
to the US. The ultimate police state is
the United States. Go to New York City,
go to Time Square, look around, you will
see tourists. Majority of the people you
see there are tourists, okay? But you'll
see locals and so on. But one thing you
will notice is plenty of cops. Not just
in Times Square. Go around New York,
travel, walk around, go by taxi,
whatever. Go to Manhattan, go to the
Bronx, go to Harlem, go wherever,
go to go to New Jersey if you wish down
south.
What you will see is you will see cops
everywhere. Cops, cop cars patrolling
the streets all the time, cops
everywhere, very ostentatiously
displaying their weapons and so on. The
moment you take away the cops,
hypothetically, if you do a thought
experiment, hypothetical thought
experiment, remove the cops, you know,
flip a switch and the cops disappear for
1 hour. If the cops disappear for 1
hour, there's going to be looting and
rioting on the streets of New York. The
society is barely kept under control by
the threat of deadly force. That is the
US for you. It's a police state
and it's a nation that's armed to the
teeth. It's a very violent nation. To
understand why they are so violent, you
have to understand America.
You have to understand America. You to
understand their history. You to
understand their origins. You to
understand Jamestown.
The Americans don't want to recognize
Jamestown as the true foundation of the
nation. They want to say Plymouth is the
foundation of our nation. No. Before
Plymouth came, Jamestown, Jamestown
showed what the US actually is. It was
it was in in a sense, you know, it it it
was an omen of what the US society was
would would eventually be like. And then
you had the Wild West. What you see in
the movies is obviously exaggerated, but
yeah, the Wild Frontier, the push
westwards and so on.
And the fact that the US is a nation
that's founded on violence on on
genocide on slavery unfortunately it's
true right so because of that
a lot of that is is is there in the DNA
of the nation you know the Englishmen
the English
like to you know aim jibes at Australia
they say it's a nation of convicts the
English say that Ian Botham once said
that it'll be fun to play in Sydney in
front of 80,000 convicts. He once said
that before before an ashes tour,
cricket tour, right? He also said that
the only place was worth in Australia to
send your mother-in-law to is Pakistan.
He also said that. So anyway, so if
Australia as a nation of convicts and
that is there in the blood then
and if if the if your past deeds remain
in your blood in your DNA then the past
deeds of the US is also going to remain
there right in their blood. So that's
why you will see this. You will you So
it's it's it's not surprising to me at
all that you see so many videos on
social media of Americans fighting,
looting, shooting, shouting, uh god
knows what else, getting arrested all
the time. It's it's not like it happens
all the time everywhere in the US, but
it's more common place than in countries
than in other countries. All right.
Abhishek Shivasam says, "What is the max
earthquake we can have?" Well, the
greatest most powerful earthquake that
has ever been recorded
was what 9.6 9.7 9 was it 10 plus on the
RTER scale. Uh look, the Anderman
earthquake was one of the top three I
believe the 2004 Anderman earthquake it
was 9 I don't know close to 10 on the
RTOR scale. I suppose around 10 is the
maximum you can have. Beyond that, it's
just like explosions.
Let's let's Google this, right? I don't
remember exactly, you know, top uh top
10 earthquakes
quakes in the world
by by magnitude.
Okay, let's let's Google this. Let's
see. So you had a 9.5 in Chile 1960 9.2
2 in uh Alaska 1964. 9.1 is the Sumatra
Andaman earthquake 2004. Then 9.1 was a
Tohoku earthquake. Unfortunate event in
in Japan. Sumatra was even worse
obviously.
Then you had 52 Kamchatka. So 9.5 seems
to be the most powerful earthquake ever
recorded.
It doesn't necessarily mean that it's
the most powerful earthquake that ever
happened. It's the most powerful ever
recorded. You have undersea earthquakes
that nobody records by the way. H
uh especially in in zones that are you
know sparsely inhabited and so on. And
see for example when you had the
explosion of Krakatawa the Krakatawa
volcano in Indonesia in the what 18th
19th century whenever that sound was
heard across the world
that would have caused an earthquake
that is beyond you something you can
imagine. Then you had the explosion of
of the Tambbora volcano in the same
region in Java Sumatra wherever
Indonesia that also would have had a
caused very powerful earthquakes.
Then you had we we discussed Toba
earlier, right? A super volcano eruption
that caused a volcanic winter that
lasted a decade, no sunlight for a
decade roughly. When that volcano went
off, assuming it was one explosion,
initial explosion, it would have caused
cataclysmic damage. Well, the entire
planet's
crust would have rung like a bell.
And when the chick impact event happened
66 million years ago,
it led to the it caused the extinction
of the non-avian dinosaurs. the Chuk
Chalobe impact event it caused
supersonic tsunamis which were like 2
kilometers high so imagine the
earthquakes that would have been like
god knows what 15 or the earthquake
erector scale 20 I don't know so uh it
depends if you if you're just talking
about natural earthquakes caused by
tectonic activity I think 10 is around
the maximum you could potentially have
but if you're talking about volcanic
events which are also tectonic events of
course but not quite tect tectonic
that's not quite tectonic right there is
an element of tectonism in that but yeah
so if you have volcanic events it may go
higher than that on the scale and impact
events well that's a whole different
scale
right
areu says why do you refrain from
talking about juice are you talking
about the Jews or no oh are are you the
person who asked the question about
noses
why do I refrain from talking about Jews
I spoke about the Jews. I spoke about
the Cypress issue. I spoke about Israel.
Are you trying to say that I I I I
refrain to talk about the Jews?
Um I am equally diplomatic when I talk
about everybody. Whether I talk about
whatever religion, there are certain
religions I don't talk about because I'm
not an expert in that. Judaism is once
again one of the religions that I'm not
an expert in. I do talk about Israel. I
do talk about Palestine. We just took a
question about Gaza. So I I don't have a
policy that I refrain to talk about the
Jews. There are things that I haven't
studied. There are people who say that,
you know, the Jews control the world.
Well, I haven't studied that. There are
people who say that the Jews control um
the US economy or the US or whatever. Um
listen, I haven't studied all of that.
So if I have not studied that, if I have
not read books, there are people who
talk about what Kazaria or whatever. Not
sure what that is but apparently it's
the original homeland of Jewish people
or something like that. I I haven't
studied everything in the world and
whatever I haven't studied I don't speak
about it. It's a very clear policy that
I have. I do speak about Israel. I have
spoken about the fact that Indian Jews
who got converted who who converted to
Judaism and went to live in Israel they
were treated like secondass citizens.
You you can see the videos on my
channel. So it's not like I refrain from
talking about them but I only spoke
speak about what I know and what I
understand to a to a certain extent to a
to a good extent. Whatever I'm not clear
about I don't speak about it. It's a
very clear thing. You can also say that
I don't speak about Islam. Of course I
don't speak about Islam. I don't know
anything about Islam. It's not something
I'm any kind of an expert in. So that's
the kind of policy I have. I think it's
a logical policy. Speak about what you
understand. Stay out of things you don't
understand and you've not studied.
That's how ideally everybody should live
their life.
Sumit says digital ID to be in the UK.
Why West is controlled freak? The UK is
going down the road of Nazi Germany. The
third
digital ID everybody will be controlled
24 by7.
Yes. Everybody will have a social credit
score now. And if you're naughty, they
will not get access to whatever.
Yes, the US, the UK is going down the
road of Nazi Germany and the Il Dulce
Shim Mussolini
and the Chinese Communist Party.
Fantastic.
Rohil says, "How can India build a more
efficient citizencentric system in
parallel to IAS, IPS without provoking
resistance from the effective from the
existing bureaucracy?"
I'll tell you what, there's one thing
that needs to happen in India. End
corruption.
It is allegedly said that hypothetically
the entire country hypothetically
allegedly runs on corruption.
Okay? If you want a more efficient, more
cit citizenric system in parallel with
whatever exists,
start a war on corruption. Even if you
remove the alleged corruption by even
50%.
It's going to be a way more efficient
citizencentric system than you can
imagine that you can possibly have
today.
That's the number one thing India needs.
Number one thing which will change
everything which will transform
everything is a war on this alleged
corruption that allegedly is the
backbone of the entire thing that runs
the alleged country. Not the alleged
country but you get what I mean right?
You get you get what I mean? That's what
needs to happen. That's what needs to
happen. That will solve all the
problems. All the alleged problems
allegedly.
Raavarura says Pakistan is getting
support all over the world. US, China,
UAE. Really? How will this set the stage
for bat for now?
Listen, we have two choices.
We either become a vasal again and we're
going to have another 150 years 250
years of East India Company like rule or
we can try and stand up for ourselves in
which case we'll be alone
but are we really alone if we are if we
are 1.4 4 billion of us,
right? And those who will be used as
tools against us will get support from
whoever is opposing us and whoever
doesn't want us to stand on our two
feet. So that is the way it's always
going to be. If you are
someone who wants to grow, someone who
wants to rise, if you want to reclaim
your original position as the world's
biggest economy and so on, well, the
ones who are currently the biggest
economy, they will not want this to
happen. So, you have the choice of
either remaining where you are a
mediocre little nation of losers or you
reclaim the greatness that is deservedly
yours. Right? So, that's the situation
we face right now. How will this set the
stage for Bharat right now? We have to
be we have to get used for the world to
be tougher than what it is.
The past 20 years India Indians have
been able to travel all across the
world. H1B vas are very easy to get blah
blah blah. Now it's going to be tough.
Everything is going to be tough for
India. And that's what we need to get
used to. We need to get ourselves used
to for the next 20 years. If we can
somehow
ensure that over the next 20 years we
keep on growing as an economy and we
don't get vasalized then in 20 years the
world will become way easier once again
it's a question of surviving 20 years of
tough times
that's what India needs to do because if
we continue growing our economy at 6.5%
even 6.5% per year for 20 years we're
going to be a whole different beast in
20 years and the world will not be able
to push us around the way they do right
now. So that's what India needs to do.
We are not a hegemonic nation. We are
not an expansionist nation. We don't
invade other countries. We don't
colonize and and destroy other
countries. We have never done that. All
we want is that you leave us alone. We
will we will have good relations with
everybody who wants to work with us.
And we just want to do what we can the
best we can for ourselves. That's it. It
doesn't have to come at anybody else's
cost.
Right.
G GG SSS says I discovered you from the
beer bices podcast. Okay. Please make it
a point to appear on other podcasts so
the others can discover can learn basic
geopolitics. I wasn't aware of non-s
sovereign actors. Most people don't even
realize. Well, these concepts that I
speak about are actually pretty simple
once you understand them. And then you
think why on earth does no one discuss
this? But no one does because the
simplest and most common sense things
are the hardest to discover. Once you
understand the concept, it it be it it
becomes like it's common sense. But you
know that's a reason why they say that
common sense is not that common. Uh so
I'm glad that um you know I've been able
to impart some of this understanding to
whoever seeks it. I will be very happy
to keep on keep on doing this. I'll be
happy to uh appear on other people's
podcasts. I'm I'm very happy to I don't
care if it's a big channel, small
channel. You will you will see me
appearing on small so-called small
channels, podcasts also. All I require
is that the host, the person I speak
with should be intelligent and should be
interested and I'm happy to appear on
any any channel as long as the
conversation is interesting for me as
long as I enjoy the conversation. So
yeah, I'm happy to do that. Absolutely.
Always.
Adi Aayu says some people in chat said
that said that Hindi is invaders
language.
These language wars need to end. Enough
of this enough. Why? Why are we fighting
about language? There are thousands of
languages in India.
Let it be whatever it is. Yeah. Hindi.
See most of the Indian languages today
have these words that have come in from
outside. Hindi if you look at the origin
of Hindi Hindi udu it's the same
language actually you know some people
call it Hindi some people people call it
Udu and this language has a lot of loan
words from Arabic Persian and Turic
languages it is a consequence of history
but the vocabulary the main vocabulary
is still Sanskrit derived and the
grammar is 100% Sanskrit derived so it's
not really an invaders language it is it
is you could say tainted
with some of the elements of the
invarious languages which we can choose
to remove
which we can choose to not use
right there. There you go. It's no
longer an invader's language. Right?
Don't do intazar. Do pratika
and so on.
There's so many words that way that can
be replaced by better words, more
civilized words. No disrespect intended
to foreign languages. I'm just saying
that we consider ourselves more
civilized. We that's why we we invented
the word arry, right?
So and and and and if you say that
because Hindi is a arian lang Indo-arian
language north Indian language that's
why it's invaders language well that's
utter nonsense you see this Arian
invasion theory it's it's one of the
bins of India it's complete lies but it
has divided India into two camps those
who believe that they are the original
natives of India dravidians and those
who are regarded as descendants of
invaders people like me we are all
natives of India there was no arian
invasion or migration it's all lies And
that's why I keep saying the education
system has to be reformed because it it
is poisoning the minds of Indians.
All right.
Vive Singh says Russia was allegedly in
Alaska airspace with the 1950s bomber.
Are they running out of air power? Many
YouTube channels are also relating or
reporting the same.
A 1950s bomber. Which one? Dupole
something.
Really? Let me
let's see. Let's see. Uh, Russia
Alaska
air airspace. Let's see what it says.
NORAD scramles jets to intercept Russian
um, let's go to news. The tupole 95 the
bear with the counterrotating
propellers. The incredible noise level.
Russian drones and aircraft have made
several incursions into NATO air. That's
fine. I'm talking about Alaska.
Near Alaska. Near Alaska. It's not over
Alaska. As far as I'm seeing over here
or over here, sorry, over here. Here.
The detection of four Russian jets in
international airspace of Alaska. Once
again, it says in international airspace
intercepted near Alaska. Near Alaska,
near near. It's all near Alaska. It's
not over Alaska or in Alaska.
That would be a significant provocation
if Russian uh aircraft were flying over
Alaska within US airspace. That would be
a massive provocation. That's not what's
happened. They're flying near Alaska.
That's okay. It's international
airspace. It's perfectly legal to do
that. So yeah, the I just checked it out
briefly
brief brief briefly whichever direction
it was. Right. So it's it's not over
Alaska, it's near Alaska, which is fine.
Brashant says, "Why is Trump mad at the
UN due to stance on Israel?" What
happened? Trump did he give a mad speech
at the UN? Did he? Let's see.
Let us see. Trump's speech UN. Did he
Trump speech
UN? Let's see. Okay, he has 5 days ago.
Okay, I haven't seen his speech, man. I
don't really pay attention to his words.
I only look at his actions. Trump's
speech uh sparks European anxiety
and so on news. What's it say? Trump's
UN speech. UN US wants other countries
to join crackdown on asylum claims.
Okay. It doesn't say anything about his
mad speech over here. Looks like he did
give some kind of speech 5 days, five or
so days ago, but uh I don't know. So, I
haven't seen his speech. I didn't uh
take the time to listen to his speech. I
don't care about people's speeches. I
just look at their actions. So, I don't
know. I'm I'm sorry. I don't know. Uh B
Mandav says, "Flower engine CV made by
Ahiraata. Please check." Okay. Happy to
check again. Let's see. Okay. Flower
Flower Engine CV.
Aha.
Ahira.
What is this?
Ahiraata flower engine known as the
constant velocity oh constant velocity
engine or CV motion is a novel internal
combustion engine designed by Ahiraata
motor corporation that eliminates the
traditional crankshaft. It uses a power
shaft and rod rack assembly and a
component called a flower to convert
piston motion into rotary motion
resulting in more continuous torque
significantly better fuel efficiency
more than 50% and a greater than 70%
reduction in exhaust emissions compared
to traditional engines. This innovative
lighter and more compact engine is being
developed for various applications from
automotive motive to industrial and this
video shows how it works. a Hiata hybrid
and hydrogen engine multif fuel engine.
Well, if what this summary claims is
true, then there should be a
revolutionary engine that should
revolutionize
internal combustion engines.
And if that is the case, well, if they
have any sense, they should make
billions of dollars out of it. And it's
an Indian Indian company. They should
displace all the other engines in the
world if they are really as good as what
this uh the summary claims. Fantastic. I
I'll I'll I'll look deeper into it. Um
and thank you so much for uh pointing
out exactly what this flower engine is.
I'll check it out. If they really are as
good as this what this uh this summary
claims that should be a gamecher and the
whole world should should adopt this
this design. But they should license the
design, right? They should patent it and
they should license it and they should
make billions or trillions of dollars
out of it. Why not? That's how it works.
Okay. Okay. Godliness says for 20 years,
for 20 good years, Pakistan was in the
Chinese camp and still somehow Pakistan
succeeded in protecting its rare earths
from them and now they're selling it to
the US. Is China the biggest loser in
this?
Certainly Pakistan the loss of Pakistan
is a big loss for China
and uh maybe the Chinese never thought
about exploiting Pakistan's rare earths
because they're exploiting Myanmar's
rare earths. So yeah, you are right. uh
from 200
2012 onwards until 2022 for a decade or
so Pakistan was firmly in China's camp.
They the two nations call themselves the
iron brothers or brotherhood is iron you
know that sort of thing. And the Chinese
never attempted to do you know any kind
of exploitation of of Pakistan's rare
earth reserves. Clearly they did not do
that. They did not even attempt it.
Uh so why is that? So were the Chinese
not aware that Pakistan has some
reserves of rare earths or were China
were the Chinese happy with what they
taking from Myanmar? I'm not sure. Is it
a lost opportunity, missed opportunity?
Potentially. Potentially. Were the
Chinese not aware of it? The Chinese
usually are aware of things. They're
pretty good at these things. So
surprising. Or maybe the Pakistani rare
earth rare earth sector isn't as good as
people think it is.
I don't think it's one of the it's it's
super rich in rare earths.
Um I don't know. So now the Pakistanis
are going to sell their rare earths to
the US. Yeah. So maybe so I can think of
two scenarios. Maybe the Chinese did do
their due diligence and they concluded
that it's not an opportunity that we
need to get into because it may cost us
more than we are able to extract out of
it. Cost bene benefit analysis.
Maybe it costs us too much, you know,
and what we get out of it isn't worth
the cost perhaps. So that's one
scenario. Maybe the Chinese were aware
and they didn't care. They didn't want
to they didn't want to leverage this
exploit the opportunity. And secondly,
maybe the Chinese were not aware of it
and they they may have realized now that
they lost a big opportunity. I think
it's more likely that the Chinese were
aware and they made the conscious
decision not to exploit Pakistan's rare
earth reserves.
That makes more sense to me. Anra says
Abijit Ayar says cold war was my German
scientist with versus Ayors. What made
German scientists so much better than
other developed countries? Well, if you
have seen, in case you've been a
longtime viewer of this channel, you
will see that in 2021,
I spoke about Operation Paperclip, how
the German V1 and V2 rockets um were
acquired by the US along with the
scientists who developed developed these
rockets. And not just the rocket
scientists, all kinds of other engineers
and scientists were taken out of
Germany, out of Nazi Germany and shipped
to the to the US
essentially as prisoners and those who
cooperated were given freedoms and they
eventually became US citizens. Um the US
space program was developed by Wer von
Brown who was a Nazi rocket scientist,
brilliant engineer but he worked for
Nazi Germany. He worked for Adolf
Hitler. He was taken to the US as a
prisoner of war and he eventually
developed the Saturn Saturn engines and
um and the the rockets that took
Americans to the moon
and
the Soviets also got their hands on
Russian scientists and engineers and
that's how the Soviets were able to
develop their space program. So the
American and space program are both
offshoots of the Nazi space program. The
world's first ballistic missile was a
Nazi missile. The world's first cruise
missile was a Nazi missile. The world's
first jet engine was Nazi. The world's
first flying wing design like the
stealth bomber was the Horton brothers
design from the from Nazi from from Nazi
Germany.
So all of the So once the Nazi regime
fell, the Russians and the Americans
scrambled to get hold of as many
scientists and engineers of the Sudik as
possible.
And that's how these two nations took
off technologically. What made German
scientists so much better than other
developed countries?
Their education system.
Yeah. Do you do you wonder why I keep on
harping about the education system? How
we need to reform the education system?
Why do I keep saying that? Here's the
example for you. Why were the German
scientists and engineers so much better?
Why did they come up with quantum
mechanics? Why how did Max Planck made
the breakthrough? How did Albert
Einstein do everything he did? How did
Vera Heisenberg come up with the
uncertainty principle? How did Schoinger
come up with the the differential
equation? The Schoinger equation
that's just quantum mechanics. How did
German engineers and scientists develop
all this technology best in its class
technology decades ahead of every other
country? Because of the excellence of
the German education system.
That is why I keep on saying that India
needs to reform the education system.
That's the kind of difference it makes.
Arpitkumar says, "You have said in the
past that Pakistan doesn't have its own
nuclear weapons. Then why? What is the
information you have?" I don't have any
hard information. It is an educated
guess. Every time I say that I don't
believe Pakistan has its own nuclear
weapons, I also said that I don't have
any evidence to back it up. Right?
But look at the logical change. Does
Pakistan have the kind of education
system that can throw up highquality
scientists and engineers?
Did Pakistan have any tradition
of highquality research? We had
scientists like Homie Baba from the
1940s, '50s,60s. We we had high quality
nuclear scientists all the way, which is
why we have our own indigenous nuclear
program, civilian as well as military,
right? It makes sense because you you
can see the entire you can see the cause
and effect chain coming that goes back
all the way to the 1940s and50s.
So in India it makes sense that India
was able to develop its own nuclear
weapons program. Pakistan what did they
have? They had nothing. They had no
scientists. They had no program. They
have no tradition of scientific
excellence or engineering excellence.
Nothing. And suddenly somehow they
developed nuclear weapons. How does it
make sense? That's why I keep saying
that I don't believe that Pakistan has
ever developed nuclear weapons. The
nuclear warheads that they may have are
most likely American nuclear warheads on
loan.
Gapati says you say that India is one of
the few sovereign states. Then but when
and how did India become actually
sovereign? We know it's not 1947 due to
Gandhi real year date. How did India
become sovereign? How did India become
sovereign?
See,
good question. Actually, very good
question. And I'm going to have to think
on the spot because I've not thought
about this. When did actually India
actually become sovereign? Right? At
what point has India actually become
sovereign? How sovereign was India? For
example,
in 1962,
1962, we had a war with China, right?
The Chinese invaded our territory. How
sovereign was India at the time? I think
India was 100% sovereign at the time.
India was mentally colonized. India was
messed up because of the Nairovian
policies. But India was sovereign in
1962.
How do we know India was sovereign?
Because no one came to India's
assistance. If India was someone's vasal
that was the master would have come to
India's assistance because India would
would be valuable to them.
Right? So India was clearly sovereign in
1962. In 1971,
we were you could say allied or aligned
with the USSR
and Pakistan was of American vasal and
we were on the point of breaking
Pakistan which is why the Americans and
British sent aircraft carrier strike
forces uh strike groups to the Bay of
Bengal and the Soviets they sent a
nuclear submarine fleet to the Bay of
Bengal and there was a stalemate there
which is why we were able to break
Pakistan and give freedom to East
Pakistan which became Bangladesh which
is now again East Pakistan. So in 71
also we were aligned with the USSR but
we were not a vasal of the USSR.
In 1991, USSR breaks up and we are kind
of lost
because we no longer have this big ally
and it is possible that sometime in the
2000s we may have been for some time a
vasal of the US possibly
to some extent or maybe the beginnings
of vasalhood but 2014 onwards once again
we are very sovereign. So it looks like
1962 we were definitely 100% sovereign.
We were not beholden to anyone. Despite
the Nehuvian uh policy and whatnot and
his great love for the Anglos and
whatnot, we were still not a vasal state
of anyone. How about 1948
India Pakistan war?
The west supported Pakistan.
Nu also took the whole matter to the UN.
But once again, so it is clear that 1947
onwards, we had dominion status which
made us still a vasal of the UK. But
once we became a republic, 1950 was it.
From then onwards we were actually
sovereign
very interesting. Very interesting. This
is a very interesting question that
you've asked Gpati sir. I'll have to
think about this more clearly but it's
clear 62 we are different. We are
definitely sovereign. 1948 the British
were on the side of the Pakistanis.
their dominion. We also dominion. So it
looks like we have been sovereign
despite all our flaws, all our setbacks,
all our drawbacks, whatever. We have
been sovereign since 1950
more or less in the 2000s where we
actually I think we were taking steps
towards American Vasal during Shri
Manuan Singh G's time but we never
properly became a US vasal. So it looks
like despite all our flaws, we have been
sovereign since 1950. Very interesting
question. Very interesting. All right.
Sumit says, "Digital ID in the UK, why
do they want to control people? Because
if you control people, you get more
power.
And people who are the least charismatic
and least deserving of power, they want
the most power.
It's because the UK and the West is
becoming more authoritarian now." So why
do they want to control people to have
as much power as as is humanly possible
that's why
okay uh CJ Joe says I also meant Israel
is buying land and real estate in
Cypress a Cypress is a fantastic case
study okay I'll tell you why you can buy
land and real estate in Cypress you have
to I don't know what what the cost is
Cypress offers people this uh
citizenship by investment
I don't know how much it costs Okay,
maybe a couple of million dollars or
something. So if you have a couple of
million dollars lying around which you
don't really need, you can use that to
buy some land and real estate or
whatever in Cypress and then I suppose
in a few weeks or months you will get a
passport.
So Cyprus allows this. Cypress allows
people who belong to other countries to
buy land and real estate and you get
dual citizenship. Then if your country
India doesn't allow dual citizenship
then you have to give up your Indian
passport. But if you belong to a nation
that allows dual citizenship, then you
can have an additional passport, a
criate passport.
So I think this is perfectly legal. And
if Israeli people are buying land in
Cyprus, I think it is perfectly legal.
Once again, of course, it could
potentially mean that Israel is trying
to gain more influence in Cypress. But
if it's legally allowed, then I don't
see why it should be an issue.
So yeah, I I haven't looked into this.
So, Israel is buying is is the
government of Israel buying land and
real estate or are individual private
Israeli citizens buying land which is a
different story. I can assure you there
are Indians also who have bought land in
in Cyprus. Okay, I'll tell you that. So,
right okay DN Singh is here. So, will
Ukraine take back the conquered areas of
Ukraine like again like the Donbas? I
don't think so. I don't think it's ever
going to happen.
Trump recently put out a tweet, right,
that you know, Israel is eventually
going to take everything back and what
we need to ensure is that Israel
actually achieves uh what Israel
achieves that is that it should retake
all the territories that Russia has has
conquered from them. So earlier Trump
was saying that there needs to be some
kind of a partition of Israel and Israel
should accept whatever it has lost lost
by now. But now he has changed his tune
and he's saying that Israel sorry that
that Ukraine should should be in a
position where it regains the
territories that Russia has taken. I
don't think it's ever going to happen.
Russia is in in a much more advantageous
position. Russia is way more powerful
than Ukraine. Russia is able to stand up
to NATO as well if required. In the past
three how many it's been three years
more than three years three and a half
years Russia's economy has rebounded
Russia's military engine economic engine
has also rebounded I don't think they're
going to do be able to do a thing about
the the territory that Russia has taken
so Ukraine will not in my opinion regain
the territory that Russia has conquered
Singh says if Europe decided to
militarize militi militarize and
industrialize again How long until they
become a superpower? Or will the Jewish
bankers funding them fear the Hugo boss
suits again?
See Europe can become a superpower only
if had if it has one single center of
power which is legitimate in the eyes of
the people. You can have a nation of you
can have a region a EU region where the
people are slaves but with a with a
citizenry of slaves you can never be a
real superpower.
So for the EU to to become a superpower
they first need to have a single center
of power and that single center power
has to be the legitimate center of power
in the eyes of the population the
majority of the population of the EU. Is
Brussels legitimate in the eyes of the
EU citizens? I would say most of the EU
citizens don't like Brussels ruling over
them.
Right? I don't the sentiment I get when
I talk to people and meet people or
whatever and overall is that the people
of the EU don't like the fact that
Brussels Brussels is the overlord, the
unelected overlord. Right? So that's one
issue. Now imagine that issue doesn't
exist and you just need a center of
power and industrialization.
So if Europe decides to industrialize
and militarize again, how long until
they become a superpower? See, right now
if you take a cumulative accounting of
the EU's uh GDP, let's let's do it live,
right? Let's do it live. Total GDP of
the EU. Total cumulative
GDP of EU, what is it?
17 trillion euros please give it in USDR
okay 19 it's it's about 20 trillion USD
20 trillion
uh GDP uh nominal GDP which is slightly
ahead of China so if you put the whole
of the EU together it is slightly ahead
of China actually
but they aren't a military power but now
they're going to they're going to invest
double their GDP into the military
domain so it would take probably at
least a decade for this to have an
actual effect on the ground of of of the
EU becoming way more militarized than it
is today. Because if you start spending
5% they're going to start spending 5% in
the next 10 years. Right now it's less
than 2.5%.
So if they if if by 2035 they're
spending 5% of the of the GDP on
military then at that time they'll start
becoming a major military power if they
are united. So I would say it will take
at least a decade for this to happen.
uh if there are people who who who have
these visions of the Hugo boss uniforms
and those marching boots then they will
not want this to happen ever. They will
not want the EU to militarize as a
single cohesive entity. What they will
do is that they will they will
cherrypick certain nations who should
militarize in the EU and all the budget
should go there. For example, Poland.
Poland is being militarized right now
and Poland probably now is more powerful
from a military perspective than Germany
already.
So Poland could be the next Bulvar
against the Russian Empire perhaps. You
know the way that the Europeans talk
it's like the Russians are going to
advance further westwards. So you need
Bulvar and Poland is the next one.
Um but yeah I don't think Germany will
be allowed to militarize. Poland perhaps
France perhaps.
um the UK. I'm not sure about the UK. So
I think even if you do a theoretical
thing, a hypothetical uh thought
experiment, it will take at least a
decade be before they they become you
know meaningfully militarized minimum a
decade.
Divor Singh says is America temporary
nation?
So how do we define a temporary nation
is the question. See the nation state
system itself is temporary.
It all came out of the treaty of
Westfallia. The treaties of Westfalia.
It's been around for like the a couple
of centuries, two three centuries.
And you already see this increasingly
that there are certain nations that are
once again behaving like empires.
The US is, the Chinese are, even the
Russians are. It makes sense that for
India also to do that if India can get
its uh ducks in a row.
Now
but the difference between nations like
India, China, Russia, Germany, France
and the US and Canada. The difference is
that
the US and Canada are artificial
nations.
Let's discuss temporary next. We will
first discuss which are artificial,
which are not. See, France is this large
entity which once had multiple languages
that were spoken. You had so many
languages that was that were spoken in
France, not just the French language.
You had the ponal language. You had
various brethn languages and so on. But
but all of that was was essentially
suppressed in the French languages. It
was imposed on everyone. And today you
have a nation called France. But it is
not an artificial nation. It is a
grouping of people who always kind of
lived there together for centuries. It's
not artificial. Germany is kind of
artificial. It was never a nation until
1871.
Um but the people they always lived
there their ancestors lived there for
for centuries. So that from that
perspective it's not that artificial.
The the US is a patently obviously
artificial nation. It's a nation that
was created through settler colonization
through genocide and slavery. It's
definitely artificial. So is Canada.
and artificial nations are generally
more temporary than than nations that
are legitimate because of historical
reasons.
So yeah, I can certainly say that
America is a temporary nation. So is
Canada
uh sorry artificial nation? So is
Canada. Is it temporary? It depends on
how powerful it is. As long as it rem
remains super super powerful, it will
not be temporary. But if it becomes
fragile,
if there is infighting, if if the there
is the center of power fragments,
then the US could soon fragment itself.
You could have states seceding from the
US like what happened in the 18 what '
50s60s 1840s and 50s, right? You had the
secession of the seceding the southern
states seceded from the from the from
the union. So the moment you have a
weakening of the power the the center of
power you're going to have this issue.
So but you could also have that in India
you know there are forces that seek to
fragment India as well. So I think
what I can say is that the US is an
artificial nation and so is Canada.
Temporary or not only time will tell. As
long as they can remain cohesive,
unified and the center of power remains
powerful, it is not temporary. But if
the reverse happens, then the nation
could fragment quickly.
Divor Singh says, "I bought I brought
receipts today. Mr. Nathan Roth shield
shorted UK bonds by knowing about
Napoleon's defeat before the crown."
Same thing happened in the First World
War. How?
Okay. Um, let me Google this because I
haven't I I'm telling you honestly I
haven't studied the Rothschilds and and
so on. So, let me Google this. Nathan
Rothchild.
Nathan Rothchild. N A T H.
Okay. So, who was Mu Nathan Roshchild?
He was a British German banker and
businessman. Okay. And he was born in
1777, died in 1836 at the age of 58. And
what are his great achievements? Let's
see.
moved to England.
Um, gold security. Ah, Napoleonic Wars.
So, he began a deal in gold bullion and
so on.
Waterloo bought brought a many million
pound scoop. Okay.
Um, and they claim that this is an
embellished version of events and so on.
Did get to London first and alerted the
family to Napoleon's defeat. Okay. So it
looks like they did short possibly the
bonds.
Interesting. Interesting. And the same
thing happened in the first world war.
How? I am not sure how cuz I haven't
studied this. Maybe they had uh
you know maybe they had access to
information that others did not have and
maybe the information reached them
first. I would I would have to assume. I
haven't studied this. I haven't studied
the role so I can't say but clearly what
you're saying seems to be corroborated
with what's there in the Wikipedia
article. Uh it may be disputed but it's
it's there in the article so it must it
may perhaps have uh more than an element
of truth to it.
And uh if the Rothschild dynasty the
lineage continued and they remained in
power as powerful bankers and they they
they retained the same sources of
information that it's possible that they
were able to do that in the first world
war also.
It would make sense that they were able
to do that. So possibly that way but I
haven't studied this in detail so I
can't tell you exactly how. But
interesting interesting clearly what
you're saying is it's kind of
corroborated by Wikipedia.
Shivan Bakshi says, "Is India at a real
risk of bulcanization?" Okay, we have
crossed 2 hours 20 minutes. I should end
this soon. So, please everyone stop
taking super chats. I'll finish the ones
that we have. Okay. Is India at a real
risk of balconization?
It is.
If you have a government in Delhi that
is not powerful enough, if you have a
weak leadership, India will be at real
risk of bulkanization. It could happen
very rapidly. Yeah. Why is that? It's
because of the federal system of India.
It's because of the Indian population
that is that is divided against each
itself. It's because of the consequence
of the of the education system. It's
because of the arian invasion theory
which makes people think that they are
some people are natives and some are
invaders. It's because of the religious
divides that have been created in the
Indian Indian population. It's because
of the industrial scale Christian
conversation conversion conversion
religious conversion that's happening in
various parts of India. All of these
activities are designed to eventually
balkconize India. So India is at real
risk of balconization. Yes, India is.
Divor Singh says 84% of Bal Bolsheviks
were Jews. They killed 60 million
Christians and all we remember is that
the Jews died in the Holocaust. Albanian
genocide was probably worse. Was it?
Okay. Let's see. Let's see if this is
true. Uh is it okay? 84%
of
Bolsheviks
were Jews. Was it true? Let's see.
Jews. Is this true? Let's see.
No, the claim is false. It's a common
anti-semitic trope. Okay. Uh this is
what the the this AI says. It's an AI
overview from Google. According to a
1907 estimate, only 10% of Bolsheviks
were Jewish. In a later Bolshevik party
census show that Jewish members made
only 5.21% of the party. So key facts,
minority, not a majority, anti-semitic
origins. This false claim was used by
anti-semites and enemies of bulchism to
create a political slur conflating
communism with Jewish interests and so
on.
The internationalist and atheistic
ideology of the Bolsheviks was in fact
incompatible with Jewish and so on. So
it looks like it's not true. At least
that's what this AI tells me. And the
Jewish bulish bullsheism, what's it say
over here? Percentage. These are a
percentage sign that I can search for.
Percentage
5.21% 6% and so on. So once again, what
these articles claim and what the AI
claims is that it's only five or 6%. Or
10% or whatever. Once again, I have to
remind people that you cannot always
trust what Wikipedia says. And AI also,
you can't always trust it. But whatever
it says is that it's not true. And what
about the Albanian genocide? Let's see.
Was there a genocide in Albania?
Albanian genocide. Let's see.
Albanian genocide. Mal massacres of
Alban. The Balcon wars the first which
preceded the first world war. Okay. So I
haven't really studied the Albanian
genocide. So I can't say. So uh Divor
Singh G what the AI says what Wikipedia
says is that no it's not 84% that's an
anti-semitic trope the Jews are only 5%
or 6% or 10%. So I don't know I haven't
studied this part of history. I haven't
looked at things from a from a religious
perspective from you know I haven't
studied this so I can't really say but
uh yeah we saw what we saw just now.
Okay.
Divor Singh says was 911 an inside job?
Well Tucker Carlson seems to believe so.
Tucker Carlson is putting out videos on
his YouTube channel saying that 91 911
was a cover up that the the truth hasn't
been told to the people of the of the
United States.
And u if it's a cover up, it could
indicate it's an inside job. I'm not
sure. Um so I don't don't know. I think
that there are elements of 911 that
don't make a lot of sense. How did those
buildings just collapse? Buildings made
with steel frames. I remember Donald
Trump came on TV that day on 911 and he
said that it's not possible for these
buildings to collapse because he had
seen these buildings being constructed.
He was a he is a real estate developer
in New York. He had seen the
construction of these buildings when
they were being built and he he had seen
the steel frames around the buildings.
It's it's impossible for such steel
frames to just disintegrate into dust.
So Trump himself hinted on that day. I'm
sure you can find the clip on YouTube.
So Trump himself said that this could
not have happened. So looks like there
could have been some kind of cover up
like Tucker Carlson is alleging. It's
possible. I think I think there is more
to this than meets the eye.
What were the dancing Israelis? I have
no idea. Let's Google it. Dancing
Israelis. Let's see.
Dancing Israelis. What is this?
September 11 attacks advanced knowledge
conspiracy.
It's a term used to describe various
dances performed by people in Israel.
Okay, I'm sure this is not what Dn Singh
is talking about. I think he's talking
about this one.
September 11 attacks advanced knowledge
conspiracy theories. Do we have dancing
Israelis here?
Dancing Israelis? Really? So on se in
September 2011, the New York Times and
Israeli newspaper Harets reported that 4
hours after the after the attack, the
FBI arrested five Israelis who had been
filming the smoking skyline from the
roof of a white van in the parking lot
of an apartment building for puzzling
behavior. They were charged with
illegally residing in the US and working
there without permits. The Israelis were
said to have pulled into the parking lot
after the destruction of the first tower
and videotaped the remainder of the
disaster with what was interpreted as
cries of joys and mocker joy and
mockery. The incident became known as
the d as the dancing Israelis in
conspiracy theory circles
and so on. So it looks like what Dn
Singh is talking about is this this
particular uh incident which seems to
have actually happened because it was
apparently reported by the New York
Times and Harets's
So it looks like this actually happened.
So yeah, I I I'm not aware of this, but
interesting. Interesting. What happened
to these people? They were held in in
detention for like 2 months. Let's read
read further. They they searched the van
and found about $5,000 in cash, foreign
passports, a box cutter. Uh the men were
held in detention for more than 2 months
during which they were subjected to
interrogation and polygraph tests before
being deported back to Israel. Back
home, several of the men appeared on
Israeli TV capture and one of them said
that the fact of the matter is that we
are coming from a country that
experiences Taylor daily. Our purpose
was to document the event
and so on. Okay, I'm not going to read
the whole thing, but it looks like there
were some Israelis, five Israelis who
behaved in a very suspicious manner who
were arrested in New York. The arrests
were reported by the New York Times and
by Haritz. They were denained for 2
months and then deported to Israel.
Yeah,
Shivan Bakshi says, "I think China is
still super vulnerable despite being
efficient and powerful, but the US is
much more stellar and stable. Truly the
ultimate superpower.
The US is way more powerful than China
and they have things under control,
properly under control. No question
about it. China is way more vulnerable
than the US. So I agree with you. So the
US has more than 700 extr territorial
military bases all across the world and
these are run super efficiently. There
are no issues. There are no logistical
issues, no supply issues. Everything is
running smoothly. People don't even
realize there are more than 130 US bases
in Japan. Similar number possibly more
than 100 in South Korea. Doesn't even
anyone even realize this. This operation
is so smooth
and they have the world's best
technology. They have more than 4,000
nuclear warheads. God knows how many
actually they may have and yeah they are
in in the forefront of almost every
technology in every domain. So they are
obviously at the peak the pinnacle of
their hard power. So I think the these
reports of the impending uh
collapse of US hedgemony or impending
impending decline of US hedgemony. these
these reports and these uh stories are
are way too premature.
ADB says many people say beyond the oil
and gas revenues running Moscow, Russia
is a failed state. What's my opinion? By
the way, have you visited Russia or any
Central Asian nation? I have not visited
Russia. I have not visited any Central
Asian nation. I would love to visit all
these nations. I would love to visit
them all. Um many people say Russia is a
failed state beyond oil and gas
revenues.
I don't think Russia is a fail state.
The what's the definition of of a failed
state? A state where you don't have
administration, you don't have
governance, where you have uh people who
don't hold legitimate power, who have
who have actual power and who are
running the show, there is no law and
order, there is no government or less
law and order, less government and so
on. Pakistan is an example. The
government should be running the country
but it's the military who's running the
country and the terrorists who are
running running the country and
terrorists get more protection than
civilians and so on. That's a failed
state. Is Russia like that? Absolutely
not. I don't think so. I wouldn't agree
with that. Divor Singh says when will we
sorry now will we eventually inherit a
destroyed world after the rule of the US
empire? US Samson equivalent would
destroy everything while going down.
Yeah. Um you make a fair point here. The
Israelis have something called the
Samsung option and it was possibly
leaked leaked out a few months ago and
it it it had a list of various
world capitals. Okay. So the Samson the
Israeli Samson option is well known that
if Israel goes down, it'll take out all
of its neighbors before it goes down. If
we go down, we're going to destroy you
all all as well. So that essentially is
is mutually assured destruction and that
makes sense because Israel is surrounded
by by by enemies. Now the US has its own
version of of the Samsung option. It has
the original Samsung option and it is
far worse than Israel. The US Samsung
option is that if if the US goes down,
they will nuke every country in
existence. Nothing survives if we go
down. That is the American Samson
option. They will nuke India despite
India having never done a thing against
them. Right? So that's the American
Samson option. So if the US goes down
someday, every empire eventually
declines and disintegrates. Every empire
in human history has gone through this.
It eventually does disintegrate and and
dissolve. So when this happens, whenever
it happens, maybe 100 200 whatever
years, will the US destroy the whole
world while going down? That would be
horrific, right?
So if that is the case then yeah if if
that's what the US does if that's what
the US chooses to do then I think we
will definitely inherit a destroyed
world after the end of the US regime
definitely and it won't be just a
destroyed world it will be a poisoned
world
if if they launch a global nuclear
attack
then you're going to have a nuclear
winter that lasts a decade which means
that 90% plus of the human population
will die out and what will we inherit? I
mean it's it's going to be horrific if
if it actually happens. But yeah, that's
this that's the scenario that they have
in mind. If they go down, they destroy
everything.
Um Dor Singh says, should we spend money
on space programs? Many people dislike
spending on space when we can spend on
social facilities.
I think we should spend on space. See
for example if you if you look at this
from the perspective of a nation like
India in the 20th century India spent
money on a space program when India was
in abject poverty India was indeed in
object poverty at the time India's GDP
was growing at what 1% 2% per year the
neuvian rate of growth and most Indians
were really poor really poor most
Indians did not have footwear those days
at that time India spent money on the
space program. Today India is in in a
much better position and because of the
money that was spent on the space
program at the time today India is
completely sovereign in space. India can
launch its own satellites, its own spy
satellites, military satellites. India
has been able to develop um and deploy
ballistic missiles and all kinds of
missiles. Because of the investments
India made on this seemingly wasteful
thing in the 20th century, it has
ensured that India is not dependent on
other nations. India would not be a
sovereign country today without its
space program. So I think it's very
important that you know things that seem
like wasteful expenditure, you also
spend money on that because of because
you have to think of it as a long-term
investment. Let's say the Americans
implement their Samsung program and they
start ning the world. But if you have an
advanced space program, maybe you'll be
able to okay hypothetically take a few
million people into orbit and maybe
settle them on Mars. I'm just painting a
faroff picture here. But let's say in a
100 years time the Americans decide to
nuke the entire world and and exercise
their Samsung option. If India has and
other countries have invested in in the
intervening period on the space program,
then by the time we may have rockets
that can actually take several million
people out of out of the earth's out of
away from Earth and to Mars or wherever
where you can build uh you know bases
where people can live long term. So it
makes sense and humanity eventually
should be a multilanetary species for
sure. We should eventually in the next
50 years have bases on the moon on Mars
and eventually why not go everywhere we
can go. So I think it makes sense to
spend money on space programs and on uh
advanced technologies that may not make
sense to a lot of people but are
actually valuable.
Adi AU says do a live podcast with Dur
Singh sir everybody is welcome to ask
questions. Why are you getting upset
about this?
No one's preventing you from from asking
75 questions if you want to. Right? This
is unnecessary sarcasm.
Vimnor Singh says, "Are we capable of
immense violence or is the top dog way
too ahead with the runnerups US, Russia
and China increasing the gap?"
Uh what do we mean by immense violence?
Is India capable of immense? It depends
on see I'm not sure what our
capabilities are from my perspective.
What is immense violence? Immense
violence is a function of the number of
missiles you have. For example, so if we
have a 100 missiles, we can do a certain
quantum of violence. If if if your unit
of violence is the explosive output,
that is the end stage of a missile
impact. If that's the quantum of
violence, then if you have 100 missiles,
then your quantum of violence is 100x
that. But if you have 10,000 missiles,
then yeah, then you are capable of
reasonably immense violence. If you have
a 100,000 missiles of different kinds,
you certainly are capable of immense
violence. Add nukes to that. Well, well,
well, well, well. I think India will see
we have no idea how many missiles India
has stockpiled. I have been saying this
consistently. India needs to have a
stockpile of tens of thousands of
missiles of various kinds including the
Brahmos and including the Nirbay and
whatever else the Shawya and whatever
in case India has a stockpile of over
10,000 different kinds of missiles at
least 10,000 then you could reasonably
say that India is capable of reasonably
immense violence and if you add the
nuclear dimension to it it's certainly
immense violence um I'm sure China would
have more Russia they have been
producing as many missiles as they can
non-stop so they will have possibly even
more missiles in the US right now. Maybe
not ballistic missiles, long ICBMs, but
definitely medium range and other the
KAL type ballistic missiles, missiles
and so on. Kinjal, you know what KJAL
means? It means kar. It's the Russian
way of saying kjar. It means dagger, the
kunjal missile. Uh so I think India is
capable of reasonably immense violence
but probably not at the scale of Russia
or the US.
Maybe China may be capable capable of
more violence than India but uh I think
we are reasonably well off in terms of
the capacity for immense violence.
Divor Singh says do martial societies
end up on top defeating more civilized
nations? Oh yes, of course. If violence
is your way of life as a society, you're
going to defeat civilized nations. Which
is why it's important for civilized
nations to also have a class of society,
a class of people whose profession is
violence. But violence in service of
society, you need to have a class of
people whose lifestyle is the civilized
application of violence, who are
immensely talented in applying violence,
but who control it and use it for the
right reasons. Yeah. So yeah, otherwise
martial societies, nomadic societies,
etc., they will always end up defeating
more civilized nations. That's what
history teaches us.
Rahul says, "Can you please show us the
way in raise raising our standards by
speaking in Hindi for one minute
straight? How does speaking Hindi raise
our standards?
I am not capable of speaking Sanskrit
because I'm not that good at it.
Otherwise, I would show you how to raise
your standards by speaking in Sanskrit."
I don't think Hindi is that high of a
language that raises your standards if
you speak it. I can certainly speak
Hindi. I've done many podcasts in Hindi
as well.
My point is how does speaking Hindi
raise your standards?
The only the only language that actually
raises your standards is Sanskrit. Not
Hindi.
Not even your mother tongue. The only
high language,
the only language of civilization which
actually raises your standards is
Sanskrit.
But if you speak Hindi without the
foreign words, it kind of does raise
your standards. But it is something
that's very difficult to do. which is
why I typically speak prefer not to
speak in Hindi because I'm worried that
some of those foreign words will intrude
into my speech patterns. The reason why
I prefer not to speak in Hindi is
precisely this because I don't want to
honor foreign cultures and languages by
using their words in my Hindi speech.
And I've learned Hindi essentially
as I went along. Hindi is not my mother
tongue. I' I've learned Hindi in various
part in various parts of you know some
of it I've learned on the streets you
know by interacting with street vendors
and whatnot. So the language I've
learned isn't that pure that's why I
prefer not to speak it. So I don't think
speaking Hindi
standards
I don't think so
says your thoughts on the Aratai app so
I think that everybody should adopt this
app and try it out and use it if it's
good enough switch to this app I haven't
done it yet and I shall do it I shall do
it
vivor Singh says do you think the US
Russia China are just putting up a show
of struggle and are secretly
cooperating. See, among the biggest
rivals, there is always some element of
cooperation. When you are the top three
rivals, you want to manage your rivalry.
You don't want it to run out of control.
For example, the US and China want a G2
kind of world, a bipolar world. The
Chinese can have whatever nations and
territories they can control as as
vasals and the US wants to control the
rest.
And that's what they want to recreate
what they had in the 20th century. The
USSR US rivalry. That was again a G2
kind of situation. So the US doesn't
want a G3 G4 kind of situation. They
don't want multiple sovereign states.
They just want the US and China to be
sovereign. Which is why they want to
deal with India right now. India is is
is problematic exactly for this reason
because India is standing up as as a as
a poll in its own right and India and
the US doesn't want this. Maybe maybe
the Chinese also don't want this. Maybe
the Chinese want the the Indians on
their side. So there is an element of
some kind of cooperation between the US
and China for sure. Their rivalry is a
managed rivalry.
Russia not quite so at this moment.
That's which is why Trump is very upset
about Russia and India is is not that
powerful and India is still standing up
which is why the the US is going all out
after India. So there is certainly some
element of cooperation, some element of
managing the rivalry when it comes to
the US and China and the US would like
to perhaps have a similar relationship
with Russia as well which is why you had
this this summit in Alaska but it's not
it's not that managed right now. So the
big
rivalry which is kind of managed is the
US China relationship.
Divor Singh says freemasons Freemasons I
saw their office in Colorado Coronado
Coronado Coronado San Diego NYC even
Bombay who are these do they control
London these are it's this shadowy
organization
and and they have offices and outlets or
whatever lodges they call them lodges
pretty openly you have lodges in Turkey
you have lodges I'm not sure about China
India you certainly have lodges,
Freemason lodges. I'm not sure who these
people are. Once again, another shadowy
world that I have not really studied.
But if you want to see um let's see the
the Indian Freemasons. Let's see
Indian free. So there is this thing
called the Grand Lodge of India. Okay.
It's the main governing body of
Freemasonry within India. It was
constituted in 1961 and blah blah blah
blah blah. So there are some of the
their great luminaries I suppose what
are their aims objectives I'm not really
sure what what these are if you look at
the grand lodge of India uh the the
grand lodge of the freemasons of India
let's let's take a look at it should be
pretty interesting let's get rid what
excuse me what is this so apparently
Shri Swami Viveandarand G was a
Freemason
uh who else did we have as Freemasons
this guy looks like Salman Rodi Okay.
Okay. Okay. That's okay. Uh let's see if
they have something about the history of
Freemasonry in India. Um contact
about us. Freemasonry grandmaster
past Grandmasters. What is Freemasonry?
What is it? Do they have an explanation
of what it is? World's oldest secular
fraternal societies. Long story here.
I'm not sure. Um
grand honors their projects
what is this popup it's some kind of
presentation so you you have swami vive
which is interesting you have shriatant
tati very no jd tat gi jd tata was a
freemason who else did we have pandit
mortilu was a freemason fascinating and
once again swami viveananda
so interesting it looks like some kind
of secret society that is not that
secretive
which likes to flaunt the great people
they've had and they they have offices
openly. I'm not sure what their
objectives are, what their mission is
and so on. So I am not sure. I have not
really studied the Freemasons, what
their history is, what their aims,
objectives and so on are. And whether
they control London, I'm not sure.
Yeah. Teen Talks Dharma says Russia has
a great military. The Chinese have
production. Israel is special. What does
India have to remain sovereign? Why
doesn't the US just use military on us?
See,
you need just causes to go to war. Even
if you're a tyrant, even if you're a
hedgeman,
you always want to put on the appearance
that you are a good person. Why why do
the Americans keep on uh speaking about
human rights and democracy and freedom
and all that? because they want to
portray to the world that they are the
freest society and the nicest society
and the fairest society in the world. We
are the shining light that everybody
should try to follow. So when you have
that portrayal in front of the world,
you can't go around invading nations.
So they cannot use their military
against us unless they have a just cause
to go to war. Right? That's why they
can't do it. Uh what does India have to
remain sovereign? We have our big
population. We have tremendous
population. Uh we have tremendous
potential. We have a huge territorial
extent, gigantic territory, subcontinent
size territory with all the resources
you can ask for. You have a lot going
for you Indians.
India has a lot going for it. We have a
huge maritime shelf. We have access to
the largest ocean I mean one of the
largest oceans in the world. Our
geographical location is is gifted by
the gods.
We have so much going for us but we
don't realize it because my teacher did
not teach me so I don't know because I I
can't think for myself. Right? That's
what has been done to us by the
education system. We are we have been
made incapable of thinking for
ourselves. So whatever is not in the
textbooks, whatever the teacher did not
teach us, we can't imagine. That's the
problem.
Okay. Okay. Divor Singh says, "Will we
ever achieve world peace or are we just
violent apes who will always fight each
other?
We will never achieve world peace."
Nah, not going to happen. We are indeed
violent apes.
And it's in our blood. It's in our DNA
to be violent.
Even even even if you look at the
history of ancient India whenever India
was not unified under a single empire we
had kingdoms that that fought each
other. Of course because of our culture
we did not target the civilians. We did
not touch women civilians ever. The
armies fought the armies and that's how
things were decided. But we did fight
and we had a whole class of society
which was warriors. Right?
So even the most civilized society had
an entire class of society whose
profession was warfare.
It's who we are. We are violent apes. We
will never have world peace. I don't see
it being possible unfortunately. Sadly
Dnour Singh says should we get multiple
passports? Caribbean, Turkey, Indian
OCI. Look from an individual
perspective. The perspective the more
passports you have the freer you are and
the more options you have for the for
yourself and for your family. So from an
individual perspective, it makes a lot
of sense to get multiple passports. If
you are an Indian citizen, you can't get
multiple passports without relinquishing
your Indian citizenship. I mean there
are people who will have multiple
passports and they will not inform the
government of India. Those people are
breaking the law and there are people
like that who exist.
But see from an individual perspective
it it is great if you have if you have
multiple passports because it opens more
doors for you. Definitely.
Echo says language and religious
tensions threaten stability. All these
factors threaten stability. If there is
hatred between languages in a country,
you let's say you have a country which
has the same culture civilization but
different languages and people of
different lang linguistic groups don't
like each other. It obviously threatens
stability sir. And similarly with
religion, religion is more deeprooted.
So yeah it does threaten stability.
Gapati says your your take on Prescat
Bush connection with Hitler. I am not
aware of this.
Prescuit Bush connection with Hitler.
I'll have to look into it. I'm not sure
about this. Let's let's quickly take a
look. Okay. Prescat Bush. George W.
Bush's father.
No, the 1988 Bush's father.
Okay. So this gentleman his his children
was George HW Bush who was uh the
president in 1988. Now what did
connection do we have with Hitler?
Did how Bush's grandfather helped
Hitler's rise to power? Very
interesting. Guardian Wikipedia. Really?
Really? Very interesting. Very
interesting. Hitler.
Hitler.
Okay. There seems to be something I I it
will take me time to read this so I'll
not go into it. But interesting that you
are pointing this out. Looks like there
is some kind of connection. Very
interesting.
Um, Sanchit says when will Africa rise
as a power or it won't and not anytime
soon sadly. To rise as a power it has to
be fully sovereign first of all. Africa
has tremendous uh quantities of various
kinds of resources. Uh but they are not
sovereign.
That's the major problem in Africa.
There's not a single country that can be
regarded as sovereign in Africa.
um they are dependent on others for all
kinds of things and they they have so
many structural and other issues right
so it doesn't look like Africa will any
part of Africa will write rise as a
power anytime in the near future or even
medium-term future next 50 years I don't
see it happening I hope I'm wrong for
the sake of the people of Africa but I
don't see it happening anytime soon
sadly
Gorov says did people ever land on the
moon or was there was this a propaganda
by the government during the cold war
era. There are many reasons. One of them
being the Van Allen radiation belt.
Okay, look. Did people ever land on the
moon? Is it true that the Americans
developed very massively powerful
rockets?
People saw those rockets being launched
live. Is it true that the Americans
spent like
significant percentage of their national
budget, annual budget on NASA during the
space race? Of course they did. The
money was spent. These gigantic
facilities were were constructed.
Thousands, tens of thousands of people
were employed in NASA in NASA with very
big salaries. So many rocket tests
happened. People died in the rocket
tests. You had Ed White and his two
other colleagues who died on on in a
rocket Apollo program rocket test that
happened on the ground itself. I suppose
um so if you see all of this thing it
makes sense to just put people on the
rockets because you've already made the
rockets and they're being launched right
so I don't believe this this uh story
that the Americans had a fake space
program did they land on the moon or not
once again I tend to believe that they
must have landed on the moon the van
Allen radiation belt doesn't kill humans
so that's not an issue
and it it you know you can shield
certain it does if if you have
microchips that are shielded or
radiation hardened, the radiation will
kill the microchips, which is something
that happened to a Russian um Russian
space uh mission once which was supposed
to go to Mars and the radiation fried
the chips and it it just died. So if you
take the precautions the van Allen
radiation belts won't do much you can
you can mitigate that. Aravsha says I
know it's not geopolitics but can you
tell us about Sarakur's role in guiding
Nitak? I don't have any understanding of
this. I haven't studied Sawakur G's
life. I haven't even studied the
independent struggle in that much
detail. I haven't studied the life of
Nitaki. I can't tell you sir. I I'm not
any kind of an expert in this. There are
many things that I stay out of. There's
a good reason why I stay out of this
because I don't know. I haven't studied
it.
I don't discuss Marata history in detail
because I haven't studied Marata
history. I don't discuss Mughal history
in detail. Muggle history because I
haven't studied muggle history. I have
no liking for the muggles
right um I haven't studied the the the
Dr. Ambedkar for example I don't have
any understanding of his life his career
I don't speak about that similarly
Sauurkar Nit these gentlemen these great
freedom fighters I haven't studied their
life in detail so I won't be able to
help you with this I'm very sorry about
that
um Zishan says why did the US secretary
of war war call all the US generals for
a meeting is it hap has it happened this
far or not probably not why why has he
called them for a
See generally you call all your generals
for a meeting when you are making a huge
change of some kind and you want them to
be present so that your change has
legitimacy or you are you are going to
mount an invasion. Perhaps the Americans
are going to invade Canada now. Perhaps
they're going to incorporate Canada into
the US and you need all your generals
present for this for for for this
invasion announcement or whatever. I'm
not sure what exactly it is because they
haven't disclosed what the reason is,
but maybe the Americans are planning to
invade Canada or maybe they're planning
to launch a war on the entire world. I
don't know. Something big could be a
foot. Otherwise, you don't do this.
Maybe Trump is announcing himself
president for life. In that case, you
need the general's present. I don't
know. We'll have to see.
Da Ganesh but doesn't have a question,
but thank you so much. Thank you so
much, ma'am. Really appreciate that.
Thank you, ma'am.
Jade Dev Takar says, "Your visit to to
BJ is due. I got selected in my dream
medical school hometown. Please visit
soon. I would love to have you as my
mentor. I would love to visit. Whenever
I come to BJ next, I will certainly get
in touch with you. These days I'm not
traveling much but yeah, whenever I come
to BJ, I will certainly let you know. I
would be very happy to meet you and uh
yeah, have have a conversation with
you." Absolutely. Thank you, sir. Very
nice of you. Very kind of you. ISX777
says once AI crosses the threshold of
AGI would it even be possible to catch
up and remain sovereign. It will be very
hard to do that.
See
even if you have AI crossing the
threshold and becoming AGI if you don't
deploy it in a manner that will vasalize
everybody then it is possible for other
nations to remain sovereign. Let's say I
I have the objective of of sending
humans to all the planets in the solar
system and if I use my AGI capabilities
in that direction then every other
nation will remain sovereign. But if I
am evil, if I am hegemonic and my
objective is to create a one world
government under me and I develop AGI,
then it's almost impossible for the rest
of the world to remain sovereign. So it
depends on who has the AGI in his in his
hands or their hands. That's what
matters. But yes, in case it's a hgemon
hegemonic power, it's very hard for the
others to remain
sovereign if you decide to vaselize them
all or conquer them all. Jed Tucker
says, "Buj seven sky hotel is my
mentor." All right, sir. Noted. Thank
you. Aravsha says, "Brahma had four
sons. Today we know radiation matter,
lambda, curvature, coincidence. I have
no idea. Many things like this. What's
going on? What can be done to further
look into this? a little premature to
say a say coincidence. I I never connect
science with non-science.
Okay. What is the difference between
science and non-science? What's the
difference between science and
philosophy? For example, science deals
with observable material objects and
phenomena.
Observations that can be replicated. It
deals with only the material world.
material objects, material phenomena.
Observable phen obser observable objects
and phenomena. Philosophy deals with non
material objects and phenomena. Love,
it's a phenomenon. But does it can you
can you quantify love? Can you measure
it? Can you weigh it? Can you observe or
or or quantify the soul?
So these things are non-material things.
That's in the realm of philosophy. Then
you have things that are in the realm of
religion or or or mythology or whatever
you want to call it. I am a person who
is grounded in science. Maybe it's a
limitation that I have but I respect the
scientific method and I don't mix other
things into it. So I am not the right
person. I'm not qualified to talk about
uh
you know religious matters and and and
combine them with with science or try to
relate scientific concepts with
religious concepts. I don't do that. I
simply am not qualified to do that.
That's why I stay out of it. Okay,
that's the deal with me.
Dyang Patel, no question but thank you
very much sir for your contribution.
Really appreciate that. Divor Singh says
thank you very much sir. Divor Singh G I
really appreciate your your questions as
well. Very interesting questions as
always always very challenging at times.
Thank you sir. Um Captain Saj beats says
US founding fathers oppose behavior of
the CIA. Do they? Okay, let's let's uh
quickly fact check this. Uh US foration
the US was founded foundation foundation
foundation
year
it was 1776 was it? Why won't it give me
a simple straightforward answer?
USA independence okay independence.
Ah, independence
17. Oh, yeah. Yes, I was right. 17 1776.
Now, CIA,
which which year was CIA founded?
Yeah, here we have it.
1947.
So, 1776.
I think that's a significant gap in
terms of time for the US founding the
fathers to oppose the formation of the
CIA.
I'm not sure. So I I'm not sure of the
US founding fathers opposing the
behavior of the CIA because the CIA did
not exist in 1776
or for that matter in 1800.
The CIA was formed in 1947. So
there you have it. Dimning says I'll be
back with more receipts next time. more
challenging each stream. OB absolutely
please do that. All right. All right. I
look forward to that.
Okay. With that we are at the end of all
the super chats and the live stream.
Okay. There is one final question that I
will take.
Wtiagi says racism against India has
been on the rise recently in a
especially in Australia. Why do you
think it's happening? I to so it is I
took this question earlier also but I'll
take it again. Since the year 2022,
there has been this concerted effort to
malign India. On the 22nd of February or
23rd, whichever date it was, February
2022,
Russia launched its special military
operation in Ukraine
and India refused to join the western
nations and participate in the sanctions
against Russia. India also decided to
buy more Russian oil because it was now
available at a discount. From that time
onwards, the western nations started
putting out this outpouring of of
anti-India propaganda in various
articles, various um western media
outlets like the BBC, CNN, uh Deutsche,
uh New York Times, Washington Post and
so on and various think tanks like the
Rand Corporation and whatnot. They
started putting out this outpouring of
anti-India
propaganda narrative whatever whatever
you want to call it. Then it started on
social media. It started with the
nafobots na for nafobots and then the
Russians and the chi not the Russians
the Chinese and the Pakistanis got into
it and from 2023 onwards there was this
big outpouring of hatred against Indians
on social media and it looks like the
Americans are also now participating in
that. So that is why you have this
happening and that's why there is a lot
of hatred towards Indians these days
because people are influenced by what
they see on social media and that's why
there is a rise in racism against
Indians in the western world. Australia
may be physically in Oceanania or Asia
but politically it's part of the western
world. That's why it's happening. People
are being manipulated manipulated into
being hateful towards Indians. That's
what's happening.
Okay, one last question. Dyata says u
okay my suggestions on how government
should deal with illegal immigration.
It's a huge problem that we are facing
in this country. Um I'll tell you in
the government of India had officially
stated that there are about 5 crore
illegal Bangladeshi infiltrators in
India. 50 million in 2014.
today it would be double easily. So I
would estimate that there it's it's a
guesstimate but we most likely have at
least a 100 million illegal Bangladeshi
infiltrators in this country. What needs
to be done? See recently when operation
zindur happened the government was able
to identify tens of thousands of
Pakistanis who were living in India
illegally for decades.
If the government wants they know they
can find out exactly where the illegals
are. The government knows everything.
So my my point my suggestion to the
government is since you know exactly
where the illegals are, please round
them up and send them back to
Bangladesh.
If there are any more Pakistanis who are
still squatting on Indian territory,
please repatriate them to Pakistan. And
the cookie infiltrators, the several
lakhs of them who are squatting on
Manipuri territory, please repatriate
them to Burma and deal let the Burmese
government deal with those
troublemakers. That's what the
government of India needs to do and then
do a what what is it uh whatever those
terminologies we need to have a proper
register of citizens and ensure that no
further illegal immigration happens. So
I think the government is very capable
of doing this if it wants to and Mr.
Modi, Prime Minister Modi, Modi GI
recently said on this during his 15th of
August speech address uh that uh the
country is is forming a highowered task
force to deal with the demographic
issue. Well, please do that sir. Please
10 years we've been waiting nothing has
happened. Let's do it now at least.
Let's get rid of all the illegals.
So that's what needs to happen.
Okay, there are more questions.
Captain says their values oppose what
was the question the earlier question
the founding fathers of the US would
their values oppose the CIA.
I'm not sure what their values were. If
you ask Howard Zinn you will say that
the founding fathers only wanted more
profits for themselves. Howard Zinn is a
highly respected American historian. If
you read his book, A People's History of
the United States, he doesn't have a
great opinion of the founding fathers of
the US. So I don't know what their
values were. The US is a nation that was
founded. See why was why did the
Americans fight the war of independence
against the British? Because they did
not want to pay 2% tax to the crown.
They wanted all the money for
themselves. 2% tax is too much for them.
So I don't know what the values were.
The values were capitalism. I suppose
capitalism and CIA. I don't think
capitalism has anything against the CIA.
Okay.
Mama Bucket VFX's to Tony Nadar's book
may change your perspective about what
exactly?
Let's let's Google Tony Nater quickly.
Tony Nar
Nater, are you talking about the Did you
ask the question about the space
program? Is it There's so many questions
I can't find your old questions, but it
looks like you're talking about the
space program.
Oh, okay. I I I have See, I haven't read
all the books in the world, so
This guy seems to be a neuroscientist
living in his transcendental movement
etc. I I'll check it out. I'll check out
this this gentleman. Sure. Uh Anish
says, "Thank you for the live stream."
Well, you're very welcome. It is my
pleasure. It's always exciting. It's
always fun to feel all these questions
in real time. Always fun. Divor Singh
says, "Trump just tweeted something
against something interesting against
the Middle East." Let's see his Twitter.
Let this be the last thing we do today.
Trump Twitter. What's he say? Real
Donald Trump. What's he say on Twitter?
Will it load? It should load. Yes.
Um,
this is September 15. Looks like he has
not been tweeting. Are you talking about
his other thing? Uh, Truth Social. Truth
Social.
Truth Social. Let's see his Truth
Let's find out what's he have to say on
Truth Social.
just uh let's see his actual account.
Okay, I'm not logged in so it won't show
me perhaps his What is this?
He is selling pillows. Donald Trump.
That's good. And a dog and some Jesus
crime. Some some shooting. King Charles
Camila make crime illegal again. More
dogs. We have a real chance for
greatness in the Middle East. All are on
board for something special. First time
ever. We will get it done. President
DJT. Maybe he wants to create Trump
Towers in the Middle East. Maybe that's
what he wants.
We'll see. We'll see about that. Okay,
we should Okay, there's one more super
chat. I always appreciate the super
chats, but please let's end it here.
I've already crossed 3 hours. It's
supposed to be twoour session. I'll take
this one last final super chat by
Vishno. As a developer, we need some
software ideas that we can build to help
this community to grow. What are some
solutions sir that you would live you
would love to get built for the people
of our country also love the show well
thank you so much look if you ask me on
the spot right now I may not be able to
give you a lot of solutions but one
thing we need is our own social media
platforms something that's an Indian
equivalent of Twitter we need an Indian
equivalent of of uh
of uh Facebook an Indian equivalent of a
photo sharing picture sharing thing like
Instagram and we need an Indian search
engine,
the Indian answer to Google, Google and
we need an email solution for India, an
Indian version of Gmail, an Indian
answer to email to Gmail and we also
need an Indian
highquality LLM ideally multiple high
quality LLMs and different AI solutions
that that's a lot of stuff that Indians
can build.
So these are software ideas you could
say these are things that India needs
these are platforms that India needs and
uh yeah you could start there obviously
these are not these are not small things
these are not low hanging fruits that
these are immense challenges to take up
but that's the kind of that's the kind
of development India needs so yeah maybe
I can think of more later on but right
now that's what I can tell you off the
cuff of the top of my head all right
people thank you so much everybody for
all the questions it was really fun I
really enjoyed
Thank you everybody and I look forward
to seeing you in the next episodes of
Ask Abij and wherever else. I look
forward to it. Thank you so much. Keep
learning. Keep asking questions. Keep
raising your raising your standards and
do check out my books that I'm working
on in the description. Take care
everybody. Thank you so much. I'll I'll
see you very soon. Bye-bye.